漫威影业
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译    ntexplorer  伊森先生  她画  维京人Astrid
翻译    夜蓝  临风近水  cazorp  cheeseflower
校对    everfor  草草
时间轴  吉吉家的安斯斯  和吉吉
后期     吉吉
一位名人曾说
A famous man one said:
我们总会亲手种下自己的祸根
We create our own demons.
谁说的这句话  它又是什么意思
Who said that? What does that even mean?
这不重要  我这么说是因为他这么说了
Doesn't matter, I said it cause he said it.
既然他也是个名人
So now he was famous
那这话现在就有两个名人说过了
and that's basically get said by two well known guys.
我不  还是重讲一遍吧
I don't, uh...I'm gonna start again.
一切还得从最开始说起
Let's track this from the beginning.
瑞士  伯尔尼
新年前夜
还有半小时就到新年了
Half hour till the ball drops.
-你想不想...  -托尼·斯塔克  演讲真棒
- Hey, do you want...? - Tony Stark, great speech, man!
-交给我  -我演讲了吗  讲得怎样
- I got it. - I gave a speech? How was it?
-就是个悲剧  -莫名其妙
- Pitiful. - Unintelligible.
真的吗
Really?
是我最爱的风格  百试不爽
It's my favorite kind, a winning combo.
我们现在去哪
Where are we going?
爽一炮吧  去你房间就行
Uh...to town on each other, probably back in your room.
我还想看看你的研究成果
Cause I also wanna see your research.
好  研究成果可以给你看
Okay, you can see my research,
不过那件事你就不要妄想了
but thats... I'm not gonna show you my town.
斯塔克先生  我是侯殷森
Mr. Stark, Ho Yinsen.
终于遇到一个姓侯的人了  过来
Oh, I finally met a man called Ho. Come here.
向您介绍一下我们的客人  吴医生
I would like to introduce you to our guest, Dr. Wu.
-这家伙  -这位是斯塔克先生
- Oh, this guy. - Mr. Stark.
你好
你是心脏科医生
You're a heart doctor.
她一会就爽到需要看医生了
She's going to need a cardiologist.
-再见  -还是下次再说吧
- Bye. - Perhaps another time.
一切都始于1999年  在瑞士伯尔尼
It started in Bern, Switzerland, 1999,
-那段旧时光  -斯塔克先生
- the old days. - Mr. Stark.
我从未料到当时的举动会招致如此后果
I never thought they'd come back to bite me.
怎么会知道呢
Why would they?
托尼  我是阿德里奇·基里安
Hey, Tony! Aldrich Killian.
我是您的研究的大粉丝
I'm a big fan of your work!
-我的研究  -我粉丝多了去了  他是说我
- My work? - Who isn't? He means me.
当然
Well, of course.
不过汉森小姐
But, Miss Hansen,
我们组织自您在麻省理工读大二时
my organization been tracking your research
就开始关注您的研究了
since year two of MIT.
电梯满员了
Yeah, we're full.
他真棒  居然塞进来了
Oh, wow. He made it. He made the cut.
你要去哪一层  伙计
What floor are you going to, pal?
这问题可问对了
Oh, now, that is an appropriate question.
我有意创建一番事业  我有个提议
The ground floor, actually. I've a proposal.
是我自己策划的
I'm putting together with myself.
是私人集资的智囊机构
It's a privately funded think tank called,
叫尖端创意科技
Advanced Idea Mechanics.
两张都给她  一张扔了另一张留着攒灰
She'll take both. One to throw away and one to not call.
尖端创意科技  简称AIM  明白吗
Advanced Idea Mechanics, or AIM for short. Do you get it?
知道了  你T恤上就有
I see that, cause it's on your t-shirt.
女士们  跟着那个鲻鱼头
Ladies, follow the mullet.
女士优先
Ladies first.
谢谢  我会联系你的
Thank you, I'll call you.
-要是我们能合作还真叫人激动  -真的吗
- I'm titillated by the notion of working with you. - Yeah?
对  小丑兄  我五分钟后到楼顶找你
Yeah, cheese clown. I'll see you up on the roof in five minutes.
我去赶紧来一发
I'm just going to try to get my beef wet real quick.
-好的  -你懂我意思吧
- Okay. - You know what I'm talkin' about?
一会儿楼顶见
I'll see you up there.
不见不散
Damn betcha.
不会吧  我以为这只是个设想呢
Come on! I thought that was just a theory.
原本是
Well, it was.
如果我计算正确  我们可以进入
If I'm right, we can access the area of the brain
大脑掌管自愈功能的区域
that governs repair.
并以化学方式对其重编码
And chemically recode it.
不可思议
That's incredible.
那就是说你能破解
Essentially you're hacking into
-有机体的遗传操作系统  -操作系统
- the genetic operating system of an organism. - Operating system.
没错
Exactly. Yes.
你能不能  抱歉
Can you... Excuse...
-怎么  -能不能不要动我的盆栽
- What? - Can you not touch my plant.
她不喜欢这样  她更喜欢
It's not... she doesn't like it. She prefers...
-她不乐意被人动  -不被打扰
- She's not like the others. - Interference is better.
走吧  到卧室去
Come on. Let's go in the bedroom.
哈皮
Happy.
别动她的盆栽了
Leave her ficus alone.
因为  你真的最好别碰
Because... No, seriously don't.
你是从植物入手的
So you're starting with plants?
目前为止  是的  我称之为绝境病毒
For now, yeah. I'm calling it Extremis.
-不过...  -怎么了
- Well, it's... - What?
在人身上应用
Human application.
完全正确  它能用于激活坏死组织
Exactly! Exactly. It's dentra-degree vitalization.
革命性的成果
It's revolutionary.
疾病防治
Disease prevention.
-能够改变世界  -甚至断肢再生
- It can change the world. - Even limb regrowth.
你是我遇到的最有才华的女性
You're the most gifted woman I've ever met.
仅限于瑞士
In Switzerland.
这还差不多
Mm, that's better.
-你真可爱  -眼光挺准
- You're sweet. - Wow, you're seeing things.
你差点就买账了  对吧
You almost bought it, didn't you?
我说的就是这个小问题
This is what I'm talking about, the glitch.
检查过端粒算法了吗
Have you checked the telomerized algorithm?
什么
The what?
趴下  别动
Stay down, stay here.
-没事  -趴下
- We're good. - Stay down.
你正趴在我身上呢  我没死
You're...you're right on me. I made it.
刚才怎么了
What was that?
-刚才是怎么了  -是我项目中的小问题
- What was that? - It's a glitch in my work...
她正讲到这个小问题呢
Look, she was just talking about glitches happening.
-跨年了  -不是吧
- Now Y2K. - No.
-新年快乐  -新年快乐
- Happy New Year. - Happy New Year.
-新年快乐  -好的  明早见  晚安
- Happy New Year. - Alright, I'll see you in the mornin'. Good night.
-你真没事吗  -没事
- You good? - Yep.
我在外面等你
I'll be right outside.
好的
Okay.
为什么我要讲这一段呢
So why am I telling you this?
因为我刚种下了自己的祸根
Because I had just created demons,
而且我完全没意识到
and I didn't even know it.
你知道我是谁
没错  那段时光确实美好
Yeah, those were the good times.
然后我就一路向前
Then I moved on.
在阿富汗一个洞穴里玩乐了一通后
After a brief soiree in an Afghan cave,
我再也没参加过派对
I said goodbye to the party scene.
现今  加利福尼亚州  马利布
也忘掉了瑞士的那一夜
Forgot that night in Switzerland.
现在我已然脱胎换骨
These days I'm a changed man,
第46次
Forty six.
斯塔克工业研发部
我已今非昔比  我是  你知道我是谁
I'm different now. I'm well...you know who I am.
傻瓜
先生  能让我先花几个小时来校准...
Sir, please may I request just a few hours to calibrate...
不行  第48次
No. Forty-eight.
微型转发器注射完成
Micro-repeater implanting sequence complete.
如你所愿  先生
As you wish, sir.
我还准备了供你直接忽略的安全细则
I've also prepared a safety briefing for you to entirely ignore.
那就忽略它  开始吧
Which I will. Right, let's do this.
呆呆  呆呆
Dummy. Hi, Dummy.
你头上那顶帽子真不是白给的  名副其实
How did you get that cap on your head? You earned it.
傻瓜
你在那逍遥什么呢
What are you doing round in the corner?
你干了啥自己清楚  把垫子上的血擦干净
You know what you did. Blood on my mat, handle it,
先生  容我提醒一下
Sir, may I remind you
你已经近72小时没合眼了
that you've been awake for nearly seventy-two hours.
请看这里  女士们  晚上好  欢迎来到产房
Focus up, ladies. Good evening, and welcome to the birthing suite.
很高兴宣布你们即将多出一位
I'm pleased to announce the imminent arrival
活泼乱跳  狂拽酷炫的小弟弟
of your bouncing, bad-ass, baby brother.
先给特写再拉远  打上日期时间
Start tight and go wide, stamp in time.
马克42型自缠卷推进式战衣测试
Mark 42 autonomous prehensile propulsion suit test.
启动程序
Initialize sequence.
贾维斯  放音乐
Jarvis, drop my needle.
该死
Crap.
很好  我看行  发射所有部件
Alright, I think we got this. Send 'em all.
好像有点太快了  慢一点  一点点
Probably a little fast, slow it down. Slow it down just a...
就好
little bit.
慢慢来行吗  贾维斯
Cool it, will you, Jarvis?
放马过来  我可不怕你
Come on. I ain't scared of you.
我是天才
I'm the best.
一如既往  先生  看您工作总是乐趣多多
As always, sir, a great pleasure watching you work.
或许三天不打盹也不算很长
And I guess seventy-two hours isn't a long time between siesta's.
没觉得情况会更糟了
Didn't think it could get any worse.
然后我非得去打开电视
Then I had to go and turn on the TV.
于是我看到了他
That's when he happened.
有人叫我恐怖分子
Some people call me a terrorist,
我则自认为是位老师
I consider myself a teacher.
美国
America,
准备好好上一课吧
ready for another lesson.
1864年在科罗拉多州的沙溪镇
In 1864 in Sand Creek Colorado
美军待友善的夏安部落的勇士
the U.S. Military waited till the friendly Cheyenne braves
出门打猎后
all gone hunting,
惨绝人寰地屠戮了部落里剩下的老弱病残
waited to attack and slaughter their families left behind,
并侵占了他们的土地
and claim their land.
39小时前  位于科威特的
Thirty-nine hours ago the Ali Al Salem Air Base
阿里·萨利姆空军基地遭袭
in Kuwait was attacked.
是...是我干的
I...I...I did that.
一座住满妇孺的古朴的军事教堂
A quaint military church filled with wives and children, of course.
士兵们都在外演习
The soldiers were out on maneuver,
勇士们都不在
the braves were away.
埃利斯总统
President Ellis,
你执意拒绝接受我的教诲  先生
you continue to resist my attempts to educate you, sir.
而现在  你又一次与我失之交臂
And now, you've missed me again.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am,
但不知道我在哪
you don't know where I am,
更无法预见我的到来
and you'll never see me coming.
信号似乎恢复了  来回顾一下可怕的...
Now that we seem to be back, let's recap some of the frightening...
网络攻击使广播中断
美国广播频道被劫持
American Airwaves were hijacked.
国家进入高度戒备状态
The nation remains on high alert.
所有对满大人的缉捕行动俱告失败
All attempts of finding Mandarin have so far proved unsuccessful.
本政府对此次恐怖活动最主要的回应
Central to my Administration's response to this terrorist event,
是刚研发出新军事资源
is a newly minted resource.
我所认识的詹姆斯·罗德上校
I know him as Colonel James Rhodes,
即将成为美国人尽皆知的钢铁爱国者
the American people will soon know him as the Iron Patriot.
埃利斯总统是如何回应的呢
And how is President Ellis responding?
战争机器重装上阵
把这个被称为战争机器的家伙
By taking the guy they call War Machine
重新刷了遍漆
and giving him a paint job.
同一套战衣  但是漆上了红白蓝三色  看看
Same suit, but painted red whit and blue. Look at That.
还重新命名为钢铁爱国者
And they also renamed him Iron Patriot.
因为这颜色实在太内涵了
You know, just in case the paint was too subtle.
焦点小组的反馈结果很好  好吗
It tested well with focus groups, alright?
我是钢铁爱国者
I am Iron Patriot.
"战争机器"那名字太暴力了  好吗
Listen, War Machine was a little too aggressive, alright?
这个给人感觉好多了
This sends a better message.
到底是怎么回事
So what's really goin' on?
那个满大人
With Mandarin.
说正经的  能谈谈这家伙吗
Seriously, can we talk about this guy?
这是机密  托尼
It's classified information, Tony.
好吧  发生了九起爆炸案件
Okay, there have been nine bombings.
九起
Nine.
公众只知道其中三起
The public only knows about three.
关键是
Here's the thing,
没人能找到起爆装置
nobody can ID a device.
现场没有任何炸弹遗留痕迹
There's no bomb casings.
你知道我能帮上忙  你开口就行
You know I can help, just ask.
我有一堆高科技  还有一件缠卷者战衣
I got a ton of new tech, I got a prehensile suit,
我还有  我还有新除弹装置
I got a... I got a new bomb disposal.
能将爆炸控制在空中
Catches explosions mid-air.
你多久没有好好睡过了
When's the last time you got a good night's sleep?
爱因斯坦一年才睡三小时  看看他干了什么
Einstein slept three hours a year. Look what he did?
人们都很担心你  托尼
People are concerned about you, Tony.
我也很担心你
I'm concerned about you.
你这是要对我说教吗
You're gonna come at me like that?
不  我不是想犯...
No. No, look, I'm not trying to be a dic...
罗德想说dick[犯浑]  因为小孩出现和谐了自己
唠叨
tator.
您能在我的画上签个名吗
Do you mind signing my drawing?
理查德这一名字的昵称是迪克[Dick]
只要理查德不介意
If Richard doesn't mind.
你不介意吧  迪克
You alright with this, Dick?
没问题
Fine with me.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
艾琳
Erin.
对了  我超喜欢你演的《圣诞故事》
I loved you in A Christmas Story, by the way.
1983年电影  是说他长得像电影主人公
五角大楼已经陷入恐慌
Listen, the Pentagon is scared.
经过了纽约事件  外星人什么的
After New York... aliens, come on.
他们需要展现力量
They need to look strong.
阻止满大人是首要任务  但那不是
Stopping the Mandarin is priority, but it's not...
不是超级英雄的事
It's superhero business,
-我懂  -的确不是
- I get it. - No, it's not, quite frankly.
这是美国的事
It's American business.
我说过我懂了
That's why I said I...got it.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我把蜡笔折断了
I broke the crayon.
你没事吧  斯塔克先生
Are you okay, Mr. Stark?
放松点  托尼
Take it easy. Tony...
您怎么从虫洞里逃出来的
How did you get out of the wormhole?
等一下  托尼
Wait a minute! Tony!
艾琳  救救我
-他说了什么  -托尼
- What'd he say?! - Tony!
抱歉  我得查一下战衣...确保  好吧
Sorry. Have to check on the suit... make sure... okay
检查心脏  检查那个  是不是大脑出问题了
Check the heart, check the... check the... is it the brain?
没有心脏或大脑异常的迹象
No sign of cardiac anomaly or unusual brain activity.
好吧  那我被下毒了吗
Okay, so I was poisoned?
我的诊断是  你刚经历了严重的惶恐发作
My diagnosis is that you've experienced a severe anxiety attack.
我
Me?
拜托  老兄  这样子可不雅观  打开吧
Come on, man. This isn't a good look, open up.
抱歉  我得走了
Sorry, I gotta split.
门卡
Badge...
戴门卡
badge...
门卡
badge.
门卡  伙计们
Badge, guys.
我在厕所都放了告示  拜托
I put a memo in the toilet, come on.
托尼把它们搁在地下室了
Tony has got them in his basement,
还给它们带了派对帽
they're wearing party hats.
我们应该把这个资产利用起来
This is an asset that we can put to use.
这么说  你在建议我
So, you're suggesting
把门卫全部都换成机器人吗
that I replace the entire janitorial staff with robots?
我的意思是我们最大的软肋
What I'm saying is that the human element of Human Resources
就是人力资源中的人力部分
is our biggest point of vulnerability.
我们应该尽快剔除这部分
We should start phasing it out immediately.
-什么  -抱歉  斑比
- What!? - Excuse me, Bambi
你刚说的是认真的吗
Did you just say that?
戴好徽章
Security.
哈皮  好吧
Happy? OK.
好吧  你上任安保主管  我很替你高兴
Okay, I am thrilled that you're now the Head of Security, okay?
-没人比你更能胜任  -谢谢
- It is the perfect position for you. - Thank you.
然而
However...
不胜感激
I do appreciate it.
自从你上任
since you've taken the post...
你不必谢我
You don't have to thank me.
我们的员工投诉率提高了三倍
we've had a rise in staff complaints of three hundred percent.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不是在夸你
That's not a compliment.
这不是夸奖吗  这值得夸奖
That's not a compli...? It is a compliment!
-很明显有人图谋不轨  -我...
- Clearly somebody's trying to hide something. - I...
-打扰一下  -请讲
- Excuse me.- Yes?
-波茨小姐  你四点约的人来了  -谢谢
- Miss Potts, your four o'clock is here. - Thank you.
你和我核查过这个人了吗
Did you clear this four o'clock with me?
哈皮  我们以后再谈这个
Happy, we'll talk about this later.
我现在得去处理这件麻烦事
But right now I have to go deal with this very annoying thing.
怎么讲
How so?
我和他共事过
I used to work with him,
他总想约我出去
and he used to ask me out all the time.
所以有点小尴尬
So it's a little awkward.
那可不妙
I don't like the sound of that.
派珀
Pepper.
基里安
Killian?
你气色不错  真的非常好
You look great. You look really great.
天啊  你看起来  也很棒
God, you look...you look great.
我无法...
I... I... I can't...
你这几年都做了什么
What on earth have you been doing?
没什么大事
Nothing fancy,
只是让理疗师收拾了五年
just five years in the hands of physical therapists.
还有  叫我阿德里奇吧
And please, call me Aldrich.
你应该拿到了门禁卡吧
You were supposed to be issued a security badge.
-哈皮  没事的  -是吗
- Happy, it's okay.- Yes?
-我们没事  -确定吗
- We're good. - You sure?
-是的  你走吧  -好
- Yes. Stand down. - Okay.
-我就在附近  好吧  -谢谢
- I'm gonna linger, right here. Okay. - Thank you.
见到你真高兴  基里安
It's very nice to see you, Killian.
伙计
Hey, guy.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
这么多年来规避着总统的
After years dodging the president's ban
不道德生物研究禁令
on "immoral biotech research",
我的智囊团终于有所突破了
my think tank now has a little something in the pipeline.
我把这个点子称为绝境病毒
It's an idea we like to call Extremis.
让我把灯关一下
I'm gonna turn your lights down.
请看人类的大脑
Regard the human brain.
等等  暂停一下
Wait. Hold on, hold on.
那是宇宙的图像  我的错  让我按一下
That's...that's the universe, my bad. But if I do that...
这才是大脑
That's the brain.
它们惊人地类似  不是吗
Strangely mimetic though, wouldn't you say?
太不可思议了
Wow, that's amazing!
多谢  那是我的大脑
Thanks, it's mine.
什么
What?
这是我的大脑内部  这是个
This...you're inside my head. It's a...
实况转播
It's a live feed.
站上来  我证明给你看
Come on up, I'll prove it to you.
来吧
Come on.
现在  掐我胳膊
Now, pinch my arm.
我受得了  掐吧
I can take it. Pinch me.
那是什么
What is that?
是初级躯体感觉皮层
It's the primary somatosensory cortex.
大脑中感知疼痛的部分
It's the brain's pain center.
这才是我想给你看的
But this is what I wanted to show you.
绝境病毒开发了我们的生物潜能
Now, Extremis harnesses our bioelectrical potential
现在看  这里
And it goes...here.
这基本上是个空槽
This is essentially an empty slot,
这说明我们的大脑
and what this tells us is that our mind,
其实是我们的整个DNA
our entire DNA in fact,
注定该被升级
is destined to be upgraded.
派珀·波茨改革斯塔克工业
你好
Hello?
是安保额头吗
Is this forehead of Security?
什么
What?
听着  我有正事呢  你有什么事
You know, look, I got a real job. What do you want?
我在工作  现在有情况
I'm working, I got something going on here.
什么情况  骚扰实习生吗
What? Harassing interns?
我告诉你一件事
Let me tell you something,
当我告诉大家我曾是钢铁侠的保镖时
you know what happened when I told people
你知道他们什么反应吗
I was Iron Man's body guard?
他们无情地嘲笑我
They would laugh in my face.
我只能带着最后一丝尊严离开
I had to leave while I still had a shred of dignity.
现在我有了真正的工作  照顾派珀
Now I got a real job, I'm watching Pepper.
发生了什么  告诉我
What's going on? Fill me in.
-真要听吗  -对
- For real? - Yeah.
好吧  她在会见一个科学家
Alright, so she's meeting up with this scientist.
-阔佬  长得也帅  -好吧
- Rich guy, handsome. - Right.
我一开始没认出他来
I couldn't make his face at first, right?
你也知道我认人最在行了
You know I'm good with faces.
没错  你是个中翘楚
Oh, Yeah, yeah. You're the best.
就是  然后我查了他的信息
Yeah. Well, so I run his credentials,
才认出他  阿德里奇·基里安
I make him Aldrich Killian.
我们以前其实见过他
We actually met the guy back in...
1999年  在哪来着  那个科学会议
where were we in '99? The science conference?
在瑞士
Switzerland.
对  没错  就是那儿
Right, right, exactly.
基里安  不  我不记得那家伙
Killian? No, I don't remember that guy.
你当然不记得  他又不是金发大波妹
Of course you don't. He's not a blond with a big rack.
一开始还好  他们只是谈生意
At first it was fine, they were talking business,
但现在有点蹊跷了
but now it's like getting weird.
他正在给她看他的大大脑
He's showing her his big brain.
他的什么
His what?
放大的大脑  她也乐在其中
Big brain, and she likes it.
让我给你看
Here, let me show you.
等一下  看到了吗
Hold on. See?
看到什么  看到你在偷窥吗
Look at what? You watching them?
把屏幕翻过去我才能看到
Flip the screen and then we can get started.
我又不是你这种科学天才
I'm not a tech genius like you.
相信我  快过来吧
Just...just trust me, get down down here.
翻转屏幕  让我看到他们在做什么
Flip the screen, then I can see what they're doing.
我不会  我不会翻转屏幕
I can't! I don't know how to flip the screen!
别再那样对我说话了
Don't talk to me like that anymore.
你可不是我老板
You're not my boss.
我又不为你工作
Alright, I don't work for you.
我不信任这家伙
Now I don't trust this guy.
他还带了个鬼鬼祟祟的家伙
He's got another guy with him, he's shifty.
-放松点  -真的吗
- Relax. - Seriously?
我只是让你守住周边
I'm just asking you to secure the perimeter.
让他出去喝一杯什么的
Tell him to go out for a drink or something?
你知道吗  你真的应该
You know what? You should take more
好好关注一下事态发展
of an interest in what's going on here.
这女人是你生命中最美好的际遇
This woman... this woman's the best thing that ever happened to you,
而你呢  你却不知珍惜
and you... you're just ignoring her.
巨型大脑吗
A giant brain?
没错  巨型大脑  还有个鬼祟之徒
Yeah, there's a giant brain, there's a shifty character.
我要去跟着他
I'm gonna follow this guy.
查他的车牌  要是他来硬的  那就来吧
I'm gonna run his plates and if it gets rough, so be it.
我想念你  哈皮
I miss you, Happy.
我也想念你
Yeah, I miss you too.
但是想念以前的样子
But the way it used to be.
现在你都跟超级英雄朋友泡在一起
Now you're off with the 'superfriends',
我都不知道你什么情况了
I don't know what's going on with you anymore.
世界越来越奇怪了
The world's getting weird...
抱歉  我得挂断你了
Hey, I... I'd hate to cut you off.
-你带着电击枪吗  -怎么了
- Do you have your taser on you? - Why?
人力资源部好像有个女孩
I think there's a gal in HR
在试图偷打印机墨水
who's trying to steal some printer ink,
你应该过去教训她一下
you should probably go over there and zap her.
好极了
Yeah, nice.
想象一下  如果你可以侵入
Imagine if you could hack into the hard drive of
任何生物体的"硬盘"  然后重组其DNA
any living organism and recode its DNA.
那太惊人了
It would be incredible.
不幸的是  听起来也很有武器化前途
Unfortunately, to my ears it also sounds highly weaponizable.
比如改造士兵  和私人军队  托尼他...
As in enhanced soldiers, private armies, and Tony is not...
托尼  托尼
Tony. Tony.
13年前我曾邀请托尼加入AIM
You know, I invited Tony to join AIM thirteen years ago,
他拒绝了
he turned me down.
但现在我发现
But something tells me
掌权的是另一个天才
now there is a new genius on the throne
她不必向托尼汇报
who doesn't have to answer to Tony anymore,
也没那么自负
and who has slightly less of an ego.
我的答案是不  阿德里奇
It's gonna be a no, Aldrich.
我虽然非常想帮你
As much as I'd like to help you.
好吧  我确实有点失望
Well, I can't say that I'm not disappointed.
但正如我父亲曾说的
But then as my father used to say,
透过失败的迷雾  才能窥见胜利的光辉
'Failure is the fog through which we glimpse triumph.'
很有深度
That's very deep.
但我不知道是什么意思
And I have no idea what it means.
我也不懂  我爸就是个傻瓜
Well, me neither. He was kind of an idiot, my old man.
我们一定会再见的  派珀
I'm sure I'll see you again, Pepper.
哈皮
Happy...
车备好了  你准备好出发了吗
The car is ready, if you're ready to go.
嗯  我只是...
Yes. I just um...
忘了点什么东西  我得去...
God, I forgot my other thing, so I'm just gonna...
圣诞快乐  派珀
抱歉我来晚了  我刚才在  这是什么
I'm sorry I'm late. I was... What the...? What is that?!
你在屋里也要穿了吗
You're wearing this in the house now?
那是什么  马克15型吗
What is that, like Mark 15?
马克42型
嗯  差不多吧
Yeah. Something like that.
人总得有个爱好
You know everybody needs a hobby.
你非得在客厅里穿着你的爱好吗
And you have to wear your hobby in the living room?
新衣服要适应
Just breakin' it in.
你明白吧  裤裆那里总是有点紧
You know, it's always a little pinchy in the gooey bag at first, so.
你看到你的圣诞礼物了吗
Did you see your Christmas present?
看到了
Yes, I did.
我没办法错过那么大的圣诞礼物
I... I don't know how I could have missed that Christmas present.
能搬进门来吗
Is it gonna fit through the door?
这个问题问得好
Well actually, uh...it's a good question.
明天我叫了一队人来
I got a team of guys comin' tomorrow,
-他们会把墙炸了  -好吧
- they're gonna blow out that wall. - Okay.
今天忙不忙  还是挺好
So, uh... tense? Good day?
按摩一下肩吧  你这个调皮的小女孩
Ooh shoulders, a little naughty. Naughty girl.
我不想啰嗦  不过你喜欢那订制的兔子吗
I don't wanna harp on this, but did you like the custom rabbit?
我喜欢吗
Did I like it?
俘虏了你的心  对吧
Nailed it, right?
我很感激你的心思
I appreciate the thought very much.
你为什么不掀起面罩  给我一个热吻呢
So why don't you lift up that face mask and give me a kiss?
哎呀  该死  打不开
Yup, dammit. No can do.
你要不要亲在...
You wanna just kiss it on the...
面罩缝上
The facial slit?
那不如我去车库
Well, why don't I run down to the garage
找个撬棍把它弄开
and see if I can't find a crowbar to shimmy that thing open?
撬棍  真棒
Crowbar. Yeah.
可是车库...那个  辐射泄漏了
Oh, except there's been a...uh...A radiation leak.
我愿意冒这个险
I'll take my chances.
太危险了
That's risky.
至少让我给你找件防护衣
At least let me get you like a Hazmat suit
或是盖革计数器之类的东西
or a Geiger counter or something like that.
被发现了
Busted.
你真是无聊到新境界了
This is a new level of lame.
对不起
Sorry.
今晚是约会之夜  你不等我就吃了
You ate without me, already? On date night?
-他只是...  -你是说你吧
- He was just... - You mean you?
没错  我是说我们  只是在招待你
Well, yeah. I mean we were just... just hosting you.
我做完了点工作
While I finished up a little work.
所以就吃了一点东西
And yes, I had a quick bite.
我不知道你回不回家
I didn't know if you were comin' home
还是跟阿德里奇·基里安喝酒去了
or if you were having drinks with Aldrich Killian.
干什么
What?
怎么了
阿德里奇·基里安  你还查我岗吗
Aldrich Killian? What are you checking up on me?
哈皮觉得担心
Happy was concerned.
-不  你就是在监视我  -我没有
- No, you're spying on me. - I wasn't...
我要去睡觉了
I'm going to bed.
等等  别走  小派
Hold on. Come on. Pep.
好吧  我承认是我错了  对不起
Hey, I admit it! My fault. Sorry.
我最近一团糟
I'm a piping hot mess.
有段时间了  我一直没告诉你
It's been going on for a while, I haven't said anything.
纽约事件后  一切都变了
Nothing's been the same since New York.
是吗  我可完全没有注意到
Oh really? Well, I didn't notice that, at all.
你经历了一些事
You experience things
事情过去后  你还是没法解释清楚
and then they're over and you still can't explain 'em.
神  外星人  其他空间
Gods, aliens, other dimensions.
我只是一个躲在铁壳里的人
I... I'm just a man in a can.
我至今还没有崩溃的原因
The only reason I haven't cracked up
大概就是因为你搬来和我一起住
is probably because you moved in.
这太好了  我爱你  我很幸运
Which is great. I love you, I'm lucky.
但是  宝贝  我睡不着
But, honey, I can't sleep.
你睡着了  我就下来
You go to bed, I come down here.
做我熟悉的事
I do what I know,
敲敲打打
I tinker.
但是危险即将来临
But threat is imminent,
我必须保护我唯一不能失去的东西
and I have to protect the one thing that I can't live without.
就是你
That's you.
我的战衣  它们只是
My suits, they're uh...
机器而已
Machines.
但它们是我的一部分
But they're part of me.
这只是个消遣
A distraction.
也许吧
Maybe.
我要去洗个澡
I'm gonna take a shower.
好吧
Okay.
你也一起来吧
And you're gonna join me.
更好了
Better.
托尼
Tony!
托尼  托尼
Tony! Tony!
托尼
Tony...
关闭电源
Power down!
我一定是在睡梦中启动了它
I must have called it in my sleep.
这事不应该发生的
That's not supposed to happen.
我会重新校准一下传感器
I'll recalibrate the sensors.
我们能不能  让我
Can we just... just let me...
让我先喘口气好吗
just let me catch my breath, okay?
别走  好吗  派珀
Don't go, alright? Pepper?
我要去楼下睡  你去敲打那个吧
I'm going to sleep downstairs. Tinker with that.
你扛得住吗
Can you regulate?
扛得住
Yes, I can regulate.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
确定
Yes.
这批货不错
It's a decent batch.
别说我不为你着想
Don't say I never did nothin' for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
理解万岁
I mean for understanding.
对不起  伙计
I'm sorry, buddy.
你干什么呢  伙计  自己出来的吗
What are you doin', buddy? You out by yourself?
约会之夜吗  看你最喜欢的言情片
A little date night? Watching your favorite chick flick maybe?
没错  一部叫做《派对结束》的电影
Yeah, a little movie called "The Party's Over",
主角是你和你嗑药的女朋友
starring you and your junkie girlfriend,
这是电影票
and here's the ticket.
开玩笑吧  那不是你的东西
No kidding? That doesn't belong to you.
萨文
Savin!
救救我  救救我
Help! Help me!
福饼的真相是
True story about fortune cookies.
它们看上去像来自中国
They look Chinese,
听上去也像
they sound Chinese,
但其实它们是美国制造
but they're actually an American invention.
所以它们是空心的
Which is why they're hollow,
充满了谎言
full of lies,
还会在嘴里留下恶心的味道
and leave a bad taste in the mouth.
我的门徒刚摧毁了又一个廉价的美国山寨
My disciples just destroyed another cheap American knock-off,
中国剧院
The Chinese Theater.
总统先生  我知道这一定很令人沮丧
Mr. President, I know this must be getting frustrating,
但是这一季度的恐怖事件已经接近尾声了
but this season of terror is drawing to a close.
别担心  好戏还在后头呢
And don't worry, the big one is coming;
你的毕业典礼
your graduation.
别关电视行吗
Mind leaving that on?
好的
Sure.
周日晚上的固定节目《唐顿庄园》
Sunday night's PBS 'Downtown Abbey'.
他最喜欢看这个  他觉得很高雅
That's his show, he thinks it's elegant.
还有  让所有人都带上门卡
One more thing... make sure everyone wears their badges.
他对这种事情特别固执
He's a stickler for that sort of thing,
不然我的人不会让进的
plus my guys won't let anyone in without them.
我们在等待托尼·斯塔克的到来
We're awaiting the arrival of Tony Stark.
希望他能就刚刚发生的袭击事件
We're hoping he'll give us the reaction...
给我们一些回应
his reaction to the latest attack.
斯塔克先生  斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark! Mr. Stark!
有消息说
Our sources are telling us that
这又是一次满大人发动的袭击事件
this is another Mandarin attack.
您对此怎么说
Anything else you can tell us?
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark!
什么时候才会有人杀了这家伙
When is somebody gonna kill this guy?
我就说说
Just sayin'.
你就想听这个吗
Is that what you want?
我早想给满大人
Here's a little holiday greeting
一个小小的节日问候
I've been wanting to send to the Mandarin.
我刚刚才想好措辞
I just didn't know how to phrase it until now.
我叫托尼·斯塔克  我不怕你
My name is Tony Stark and I'm not afraid of you.
我知道你是个懦夫
I know you're a coward,
所以我决定  你是死人了  伙计
so I've decided that you just died, pal.
我会亲自去收尸
I'm gonna come get the body.
无关政治
There's no politics here;
只有老式的复仇
it's just good old-fashioned revenge.
无关五角大楼
There's no Pentagon;
只有你和我
it's just you and me.
如果你还是个男人
And on the off-chance you're a man,
记着我家地址
here's my home address:
马利布港10880号  邮编90265
10880, Malibu Port, 90265.
我的房门时刻大开
I'll leave the door unlocked.
你就想要这个  是吧
That's what you wanted, right?
我赔你
Bill me.
我已经把满大人的资料整理好了  先生
I've compiled a Mandarin database for you, sir.
来源是神盾局  联邦调查局
Drawn from S.H.I.E.L.D., F.B.I.,
和中情局侦听处
and C.I.A. intercepts.
现在进行虚拟犯罪现场重建
Initiating virtual crime scene reconstruction.
好
Okay,
让我看看
what do we got here?
他的名字源于一位中国古代的战争军师
His name is an ancient Chinese war mantle,
意思是皇帝的顾问
meaning "Adviser to the King".
熟悉南美的叛乱战略
South American insurgency tactics,
说话像浸礼会的传教士
talks like a Baptist preacher.
这里真够热闹的
There's lots of pageantry going on here...
不少好戏
lots of theater.
关闭
Close.
爆炸产生了过高的3000摄氏度热量
The heat from the blast was in excess of 3000 degrees Celsius.
12.5码内的物体都会瞬间汽化
Any subjects within 12.5 yards were vaporized instantly.
中国剧院方圆三英里内
No bomb parts found in a three mile radius
没有发现炸弹碎片
of the Chinese theater.
没有  先生
No, sir.
告诉我  哈皮
Talk to me, Happy.
什么是炸弹又不是炸弹呢
When is a bomb not a bomb?
有军人伤亡吗
Any military victims?
杰克·塔加特
没有任何公共记录  先生
Not according to public records, sir.
把热源显像图再调出来
Bring up the thermogenic signatures again,
把三千度也算进去
factor in three thousand degrees.
甲骨文云计算分析完成
The oracle cloud has completed analysis.
连接卫星
Accessing satellites and
将最近一年的热源产生绘制成图
plotting the last twelve months of thermogenic occurrence now.
除去所有满大人袭击过的地方
Take away everywhere that there's been a Mandarin attack.
加州  圣拉斐尔  热信号
这个不是
Nope.
密苏里  斯普林菲尔德  热信号
田纳西州  玫瑰山  能信号
那个  你确定那不是他的袭击吗
That. You sure that's not one of his?
这个早于任何一次已知满大人袭击事件
It predates any known Mandarin attack.
这是一起自杀式炸弹袭击
The incident was the use of a bomb to assist a suicide.
查德·戴维斯
爆炸夺走六条生命
我儿子不会的
调出来
Bring it around.
热信号十分相像
The heat signature is remarkably similar.
三千摄氏度
Three thousand degrees Celsius.
两个军人了
That's two military guys.
去过田纳西州吗  贾维斯
Ever been to Tennessee, Jarvis?
正在安排飞往田纳西州的计划
Creating a flight plan for Tennessee.
现在还允许人来访吗
Are we still at "ding-dong"?
我们现在应该是高度戒严状态
We're supposed to be on total security lock down.
拜托  我刚威胁了一个恐怖分子  那是谁
Come on, I threatened a terrorist. Who is that?
我对此无能为力  先生
There's only so much I can do, sir,
是你把地址给了全世界的记者
when you give the world's press your home address.
站在那儿别动
Right there's fine.
你不是满大人  对吧
You're not the Mandarin, are you?
对吧
Are you?
你不记得了  我怎么都不惊讶呢
You don't remember. Why am I not surprised?
别往心里去
Don't take it personally,
我都不记得我早餐吃了什么
I don't remember what I had for breakfast.
无麸质华夫饼  先生
Gluten-free waffles, sir.
没错
That's right.
好吧  我要和你单独谈谈
Okay, look, I need to be alone with you.
别在这里  是要紧事
Some place not here, it's urgent.
我一般不会拒绝这种事的
Normally, I'd go for that sort of thing,
但现在我有了个正式的女朋友
but now I'm in a committed relationship.
就是她
It's... with her.
托尼  有客人吗
Tony, is somebody there?
是的  是玛雅·汉森
Yeah, it's Maya Hansen.
一个植物学家老朋友  不太熟
Old botanist pal that I used to know, barely.
别告诉我有个我从没见过的
Please don't tell me that there is a twelve year-old kid
12岁孩子在车里等我
waiting in the car that I've never met.
他13岁了
He's thirteen.
别傻了  我需要你的帮助
And no, I need your help.
帮什么  为什么是这时候
What... what for? Why now?
因为我读了报纸  而且
Because I read the papers, and,
坦白说  我觉得你活不过这周了
frankly, I don't think you'll last the week.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
对不起  哈皮住院了
I'm sorry. With Happy in the hospital,
我不知道会有客人来
I didn't know we were expecting guests.
不是客人
We weren't.
-不  我  -旧情人吗
- No, I... - And old girlfriends!
不算是
She's not really.
不是  顶多就是一夜情
No, not really. It... it was just one night.
没错
Yep.
果然是你的风格啊
That's how you did it, isn't it?
-没错  -美好的一晚
- Yep. - It was a great night.
其实
Well, you know...
-幸好你抽身的早  -你说什么
- You have saved yourself a world of pain. - What?
-我想也是  -相信我
- I'm sure. - Trust me.
咱们要出城去躲躲
We're going out of town.
咱们谈过了  不可以
Okay, we've been through this. Nope.
可以
Yep!
男人说了不可以
The man says no.
-马上就走  短期不回  -宝贝
- Immediately and indefinitely! - Honey...
好主意  咱们走吧
Great idea. Let's go.
对不起  这是个糟透了的主意
I'm sorry. That's a terrible idea.
-别碰她的包  -托尼
- Please don't touch her bags. - Tony,
正常人都会这么做
this is how normal people behave.
在外面我没法保护你  我挑衅了...
I can't protect you out there. I challenged...
那个正常吗
Is... is that normal?
-可悲的是  -正常得很
- Sadly, that... - Yes, this is normal!
那个特别正常
is very normal.
那只是个大兔子  别大惊小怪的
It's a big bunny, relax about it!
冷静点
Calm down!
这是我送给你的
I got this for you.
斯塔克放出狠话
-我知道  -你都没跟我说
- I'm aware of that. - You still haven't even told me
你喜欢它
that you liked it!
-我不喜欢  -我问过你三次
- I don't like it! - I asked you three...
-你居然不喜欢  -托尼
- You don't like it?! - Tony,
我们得离开这个房子
we are leaving the house.
-两位  -这事没的商量
- Guys. - That's not even up for discussion.
-我们能不能...  -干什么
- can we um... - What?
我们是不是要担心一下那个
Do we need to worry about that?
我保护你
I got you.
是我先保护你的
I got you first.
就像我说的  我们不能待在这儿了
Like I said, we can't stay here.
快走  我就来
Move! I'm right behind!
带她走  我自己想办法出去
Get her, I'm gonna find a way around.
别停下  去找她  带她走
Stop stopping! Get her, get outside!
快
Go!
我的天啊  托尼
Oh my God. Tony!
先生  波茨小姐已经安全离开了
Sir, Miss Potts is clear of the structure.
贾维斯  我的飞行能量呢
Jarvis, where's my flight power?!
正在处理  先生  这只是一件原型机
Working on it, sir. This is a prototype.
离线
解决一架
That's one.
先生  这套战衣还不能用于战斗
Sir, the suit is not combat-ready.
第二架
That's two.
托尼
Tony!
先生  请深呼吸
Sir, take a deep breath.
飞行能量已恢复
Flight power restored.
先生  先生
Sir. Sir!
关掉警报  我知道了
Alright, kill the alarm. I got it.
那是紧急警报
That's the emergency alert
触发原因是能量已降至5%以下
triggered by the power dropping below five percent.
这是在下雪吧
It's snowing, right?
我们在哪  州北吗
Where are we, upstate?
我们在田纳西州玫瑰山外五英里处
We're five miles outside of Rose Hills, Tennessee.
为什么
Why?!
贾维斯
Jarvis!
我没说要来这里
Not my idea!
我们为什么来这里  差了十万八千里
What are we doing here? This is thousands of miles away!
我得去找派珀  我得...
I gotta get Pepper, I gotta...
我准备了一份飞行计划  这里是目的地
I prepared a flight plan. This was the location.
谁叫你做的  把盔甲打开
Who asked you? Open the suit.
我好像出故障了  先生
I... I think I may be malfunctioning, sir.
弹射打开
Open eject.
这才爽
That's brisk!
我还是进去待一会儿吧
Maybe I'll just cozy back up for a bit.
我觉得我现在得睡了  先生
I actually think I need to sleep now, sir.
贾维斯
Jarvis.
Jarvis?
别丢下我  伙计
Don't leave me, buddy.
德士古加油站
斯塔克安全服务器
Stark Secure Server:
现正向所有已知接收者转接
Now transferring to all known receivers.
派珀  是我
Pepper, it's me.
我有很多抱歉要说
I've got a lot of apologies to make
但是时间有限  首先
and not a lot of time. So first off,
很抱歉让你处于危险的境地
I'm so sorry I put you in harm's way.
那很自私也很愚蠢  以后再也不会了
That was selfish and stupid and it won't happen again.
还有  现在是圣诞  那兔子太大了
Also, it's Christmas time, the rabbit's too big.
就这样  对不起
Done. I'm sorry.
我还要预道歉  因为
And I'm sorry in advance because...
我还不能回家
I can't come home yet.
我得找到那家伙  你要注意安全
I need to find this guy. You gotta stay safe.
我就想说这个
That's all I know.
我刚从一个印第安木人身上偷了一件斗篷
I just stole a poncho from a wooden Indian.
坐舒服点
Let's get you comfy.
你现在开心了吧
You happy now?
停下
Freeze!
别动
Don't move.
被你抓住了
You got me.
土豆枪不错
Nice potato gun.
就是枪管有点长
Barrel's a little long.
又长又粗的话  会减弱它的攻击力
Between that and the wide gauge, it's gonna diminish your FPS
现在你还没弹药了
And now you're out of ammo.
你胸口上那个东西是什么
What's that thing on your chest?
是个电磁体  你应该懂的
It's a electromagnet. You should know,
你这里有一整盒呢
you've got a box of them right here.
它是给什么供电的
What does it power?
我的天啊
Oh my God!
那个
That...
那是
that's...
那是钢铁侠吗
Is that Iron Man?
其实  我才是
Technically, I am.
其实  你已经死了
Technically, you're dead.
满大人袭击  斯塔克据推测已死
有道理
A valid point.
他怎么了
What happened to him?
生活艰辛
Life.
我建造了他  我照顾他
I built him, I take care of him.
现在我要修好他
I'll fix him.
像机械师那样吗
Like a mechanic?
是的
Yeah.
如果是我在造钢铁侠和战争机器的话
If I was building Iron Man and War Machine...
现在叫钢铁爱国者了
It's Iron Patriot now.
这样酷多了
That's way cooler!
才不是
No, it's not.
好吧  是我的话就加上  那个逆...
Anyways, I would have added in um... the retro...
逆反射板吗
Retroreflective panels?
让他可以隐形
To make him stealth mode.
你想要隐形吗
You want a stealth mode?
多酷啊  不是吗
Cool, right?
这主意不错  也许我会造一套
That's actually a good idea. Maybe I'll build one.
这主意就不好了  你在干什么
Not a good idea! What are you doing?
你把他的手指掰下来了
You're gonna break his finger?
他很痛苦  他受伤了  别动他
He's in pain, he's been injured. Leave him alone.
对不起
Sorry.
真的吗
Are you?
没事  我会修好的
Don't worry about it, I'll fix it.
那个  谁在家
So, uh, who's home?
我妈妈出去吃饭了
Well, my mom already left for the diner
我爸去7/11买刮刮乐了
and dad went to 7-Eleven to get scratchers.
我猜他中奖了  因为那是六年前的事了
I guess he won, 'cause that was six years ago.
很正常  好多老爸都出走
Which happens, dads leave.
不用那么计较
No need to be a pussy about it.
我需要一些东西
Here's what I need:
一台笔记本电脑
a laptop,
一块电子表  一台手机
a digital watch, a cell phone,
还有你那火箭筒的气动螺旋管
the pneumatic actuator from your bazooka over there,
一份小镇地图  一个大弹簧
a map of town, a big spring,
和一个金枪鱼三明治
and a tuna fish sandwich.
有我什么好处
What's in it for me?
救赎  他叫什么
Salvation. What's his name?
谁
Who?
在学校里欺负你的小孩  他叫什么
The kid that bullies you at school, what's his name?
你怎么知道的
How'd you know that?
我刚好有你需要的东西
I got just the thing.
这是小孩玩的彩罐  开玩笑的
This is a pinata for a cricket. I'm kidding,
这是很厉害的武器  别对着自己
it's a very powerful weapon. Point it away from your face,
按下上面的按钮  能吓跑欺负你的人
press the button on top. It discourages bullying.
非致命武器  只是用来脱身
Non-lethal, just to cover one's ass.
成交吗
Deal?
成交吗  怎么样
Deal? What'd you say?
成交了
Deal.
成交
Deal?
你叫什么
What's you're name?
哈里  你叫
Harley. And you're...
机械师
The mechanic.
托尼
Tony.
知道我一直在想什么吗
You know what keeps going through my head?
我的三明治呢
Where's my sandwich?
斯塔克安全服务器  视网膜扫描已认证
Stark Secure Server: retinal scan verified.
派珀  是我
Pepper, it's me.
我有很多抱歉要说  但是时间有限
I've got a lot of apologies to make and not a lot of time.
首先  很抱歉让你处于危险的境地
So first off, I'm so sorry I put you in harm's way.
那很自私也很愚蠢  以后再也不会了
That was selfish and stupid and it won't happen again.
你今晚来家里干什么
Why were you at the house tonight?
你有什么如此重要的事非要跟托尼说
What was so important that you had to speak to Tony?
我觉得我的老板效力于满大人
I think that my boss is working for the Mandarin.
如果你还想继续谈的话
So if you still want to talk about it,
我建议找个安全一点的地方谈
I suggest that we get ourselves someplace safe.
你觉得你的老板效力于满大人吗
Your boss works for the Mandarin, you think?
但托尼说你是个植物学家  那么
But Tony says you're a botanist, so...
难怪了  其实我是个
That figures. What I actually am is
一个管理四十人小组的基因编码员
a biological DNA coder running a team of forty
受雇于一个私人智囊团
out of a privately-funded think tank,
不过你确实可以说我是个植物学家
but sure you can call me a botanist.
你的老板  叫什么名字
This boss of yours, does he have a name?
叫阿德里奇·基里安
Yeah, Aldrich Killian.
我们把房子炸掉了  先生
Well, we took the house down, sir...
但是没有发现尸体
But there's no sign of a body.
-我明白了  -没找到斯塔克
- I see. - No Stark.
我得挂了
I have to go.
大师要开始录像了  他有点
The Master is about to record and he's a little...
你知道他的
Well, you know how he gets.
今晚的约会别忘了  完事了打给我
Keep your appointment tonight and call me when it's done.
好了各位  不要说话  不要看他的眼睛
Alright everybody. No talking and no eye contact,
除非你想被一枪崩掉
unless you wanna get shot in the face.
报告情况
Report in.
屋内安全
The house is clear.
大师进来了
The Master is traveling.
好了  我们还在等什么
Well then, what are we waiting for?
三明治还行  弹簧有点生锈了
The sandwich was fair, the spring was a little rusty,
剩下的材料  我能凑合着用
the rest of the materials, I'll make do.
对了  你说你妹妹有块手表时
By the way, when you said your sister had a watch,
我没想到会这么幼齿
I was kinda hoping for something a little more adult than that.
她才六岁  再说这是个限量版
She's six! Anyway, it's limited edition.
我们什么时候能聊聊纽约的事
When can we talk about New York?
可能永远不会  别去想了
Maybe never, relax about it.
那复仇者联盟呢
What about The Avengers,
-能聊聊他们吗  -回头的吧
- can you talk about them? - I don't know, later.
孩子  让我喘口气
Hey kid, give me a little space.
官方说法是什么
What's the official story here?
怎么回事
What happened?
好像是个叫查德·戴维斯的人
I guess this guy named Chad Davis,
以前住在附近
used to live roundabouts,
在军队里获得了很多勋章
won a bunch of medals in the army.
有一天人们说他疯了
One day, folks said he went crazy
然后做了一个...炸弹
and made, you know, a bomb.
然后他在这里把自己炸飞了
Then he blew himself up right here.
死了六个人  对吗
Six people died, right?
是的
Yeah.
包括查德·戴维斯吗
Including Chad Davis?
是的
Yeah.
是吗  这没道理啊
Yeah. That doesn't make sense.
想想看  六个人死了  只有五个阴影
Think about it. Six dead, only five shadows.
人们说这些阴影
Yeah, people said these shadows are
是升入天堂的灵魂的烙印
like the mark of souls gone to Heaven.
除了那个人弹
Except the bomb guy,
他没有阴影  所以他下了地狱
he went to Hell on account of he didn't get a shadow.
所以只有五个
That's why there's only five.
你信吗
Do you buy that?
大家都这么说的
That's what everyone says.
知道这个坑让我想起什么吗
You know what this crater reminds me of?
不知道  我不...我不在乎
No idea. I'm not...I don't care.
那个巨大的虫洞  在纽约
That giant wormhole, in um...in New York.
你有同感吗
Does it remind you?
你这是想套话  我不想谈
That's manipulative. I don't want to talk about it.
他们会回来吗  那些外星人
Are they coming back? The aliens?
也许吧  你闭嘴行吗
Maybe. Can you stop?
记不记得我跟你说
Remember when I told you,
我有焦虑症
that I have an anxiety issue?
这个话题让你  焦躁吗
Does this subject make you...make you edgy?
是有一点
Yeah, a little bit.
能不能让我喘口气
Can I just catch my breath for a second?
玫瑰山有坏人吗
Are there bad guys in Rose Hills?
你要用塑料袋呼吸吗
Do you...do you need a plastic bag to breathe into?
-你有药吗  -没有
- Do you have medication? - Nope.
你需要吃药吗
Do you need to be on it?
也许吧
Probably.
-你有创伤后应激障碍吗  -应该没有
- Do you have PTSD? - I don't think so.
你要...失去理智了吗
Are you...are you going completely mental?
我可以闭嘴  你要我闭嘴吗
I can stop, do you want me to stop?
你要我闭嘴吗
Do you want me to stop?
记得我说过叫你闭嘴吗
Remember when I said to stop doing that?
上帝啊  你快把我弄崩溃了
I swear to God, you're going to freak me out!
你成功了  不是吗  现在开心了吧
Ah man, you did it, didn't you? You happy now?
我说了什么
What did I say?
等等我  等等
Hey, wait up! Wait, wait.
你这是怎么了
What the hell was that?
都是你的错  你害我抓狂了
Your fault, you spazzed me out.
回归正题  我们说到哪了
Okay, back to business. Where were we?
那个死者  有亲戚和妈妈吗
The guy who died...relatives? Mom?
戴维斯太太  她在哪里
Mrs. Davis, where is she?
老地方
Where she always is.
现在你才帮上忙了
See, now you're being helpful.
沃克酒吧
对不起
Sorry.
女士  这是
Lady, this uh...
谢谢
Thank you.
发型不错  很适合你
Nice haircut, suits you.
手表不错
Nice watch.
没错  限量版的
Yeah, limited edition.
当然了
Oh, I don't doubt it.
晚上好好玩
Well, have a good evening.
戴维斯太太  介意我坐下吗
Mrs. Davis, mind if I join you?
自由国家嘛
Free country.
确实
It sure is.
好了
Alright.
你想从哪说起
Where'd you like to start?
我只想说我为您丧子感到难过
I just want to say I'm sorry about your loss.
我想知道你觉得发生了什么
I want to know what you think happened.
我给你带来了资料  你拿了就走吧
Look, I brought your damn file. You take it and go.
无论里面是什么他都不想与之有任何瓜葛
Whatever was in here, he wanted no part of it.
机密文件  查德·戴维斯
很明显你是在等其他人
Clearly, you're waiting for someone else.
对吧  约好在这里见吧
Yeah? Supposed to meet somebody here?
是的
Yeah.
查德·戴维斯
行动中失踪
J·塔加特
戴维斯太太  您儿子没有自杀
Mrs. Davis, your son didn't kill himself,
我向您保证
I guarantee you.
他没有杀任何人
He didn't kill anyone.
有人利用了他
Someone used him.
你说什么
What?
有人把他当做了武器
As a weapon.
你不是给我打电话的那个人  对吧
You're not the person who called me after all, are you?
其实  那是我
Actually, I am.
怎么回事
What's all this about?
发生了什么事
What the hell's going on here?
我在抓人
It's called an arrest.
是警长吧
Sheriff, is it?
没错  我是警长  你是谁
Yes, ma'am, it is. And you are?
国土安全局
Homeland Security.
还有什么问题吗
We good here?
有问题
No, we're not good.
你最好把来龙去脉讲清楚
I need a little more information than that.
恐怕你级别不够高  警长
Well, I think it's a little above your pay grade, Sheriff.
那你去联系下纳什维尔[田纳西首府]
Yeah, well, why don't you get on the horn to Nashville and uh...
给我升升级吧
upgrade me?
好吧  你知道吗
Alright, you know what?
我本希望能和平解决的  但是
I was hoping to do this the smart way, but uh...
好玩的方法总是更奏效
the fun way's always good.
警官  把这个女人抓起来
Deputy, get this woman and...
辣妹  想玩玩吗  就你和我  走吧
Hey hot wings, you wanna party? You and me, let's go.
很疯狂吧
Crazy, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
看好了
Watch this.
你算是找对人了
You walked right into this one,
我泡过比你更火辣的妞
I've dated hotter chicks than you.
你就这点本事吗  耍花招说冷笑话
That's all you got? Cheap trick and a cheesy one-liner?
亲爱的  我的自传可以起这个名字
Sweetheart, that could be the name of my autobiography.
-放开我  -救命
- Let me go! - Help me!
救命
Help me!
好吧
Anyway.
孩子  你要想什么圣诞礼物
Hey kid, what would you like for Christmas?
-斯塔克先生  对不起  -不不不
- Mr. Stark, I am so sorry! - No, no.
他想说的应该是  我要那份文件
I think he was trying to say 'I want my goddamn file.'
这不是你的错  孩子
It's not your fault, kid.
记得我说过被人欺负时该怎么做吗
Remember what I told you about bullies?
喜欢吗  乡巴佬
You like that, West World?
聪明人就这样  总有办法保护自己
That's the thing about smart guys, we always cover our ass.
不用谢
You're welcome!
谢什么  我错过了什么
For what? Did I miss something?
我救了你
Me saving your life.
一  是我先救了你  二  谢就谢
Yeah, A: Saved you first, B: Thanks, sort of,
三  如果你帮助了别人
and C: If you do someone a solid,
别那么烦人  明白吗
don't be a yutz, alright?
淡定一点  不然会让人觉得浮夸
Just play it cool otherwise you come off grandiose.
你就没这样吗
Unlike you?
承认吧  你需要我  我们心有灵犀
Admit it, you need me. We're connected.
我只要你乖乖回家
What I need is for you to go home,
好好陪你妈  什么都别说  看好战衣
be with your mom, keep your trap shut, guard the suit.
待在电话附近
And stay connected to the telephone,
我打给你  你就得接  好吗
because if I call, you better pick up. Okay?
明白了吗
Can you feel that?
别再跟着我了
We're done here.
让开  不然从你身上碾过去
Move out of the way or I'm gonna run you over.
再见  孩子
Bye, kid.
对不起  孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
你做得很好
You did good.
你现在要像我爸那样丢下我吗
So now you're just gonna leave me here, like my dad?
没错
Yeah.
等等  你是在装可怜吗
Wait, you're guilt-tripping me, aren't you?
我好冷
I'm cold.
我看得出来  知道我为什么看得出来吗
I can tell. You know how I can tell?
因为我们心有灵犀
Cause we're connected.
试试也好
It was worth a shot.
没错  这款圣诞树价廉物美
You get this, it's affordable, it's gorgeous,
能搭配任何家居装饰
it goes with any decor...
画面怎么了
What happened to the picture?
我们得启用超驰控制
We'll go to override it.
他们控制了...
They are accessing the TCL...
这种事怎么又发生了
How is this happening again?
-超驰控制洛杉矶  -我在努力
- Override to Los Angeles.  - I'm trying to...
信号是从哪里来的
Where's the feed coming from?
不知道  所有接收器里都是
I don't know, it's in all of our receivers and I...
整个东海岸
We entire east coast,
卫星都中断了
the satellites are down.
不只是我们这里
not just our station...
启用紧急方案
Move up back-up manual.
有一个未经授权的节目...
We have an unauthorized broadcast cutting...
副总统先生  您得看看这个
Mr. Vice President, I think you should see this.
天啊  又来了
Oh my God, not again.
总统也在看吗
Is the President getting this?
总统先生  还剩最后两节课
Mr. President, only two lessons remain.
我打算在圣诞节早上前把课讲完
And I intend to finish this before Christmas morning.
这位是托马斯·理查兹
Meet Thomas Richards.
名字响亮  工作也好
Good strong name, good strong job.
这位托马斯是罗克森石油公司的会计
Thomas here is an accountant for the Roxxon Oil Corporation.
我相信他是个好人
And I'm sure he's a really good guy.
我要在30秒内
I'm gonna shoot him in the head,
在直播电视上  一枪打爆他的头
live on your television, in thirty seconds.
这台电话的号码已经发到你手机上
The number for this telephone is in your cell phone.
很刺激吧
Exciting, isn't it?
想想号码是怎么发过去的吧
Imagining how it got there.
美国  如果你的总统在半分钟内打给我
America, if your president calls me in the next half-minute,
我就饶他不死  计时开始
Tom lives. Go.
他怎么黑进我手机的
How did he hack my phone?
我们不能对恐怖分子言听计从
We can't allow terrorists to dictate...
这通电话我必须打
I have to make this call.
我强烈反对
I'd strongly advise against that.
我不能见死不救
This is the right thing to do.
还剩最后一节课  埃利斯总统
There's just one lesson left, President Ellis.
逃吧  躲起来吧  和你的孩子告别吧
So run away, hide, kiss your children goodbye.
因为谁也救不了你  你的军队
Because nothing, not your army,
你那红白蓝三色的攻击犬都不行
not your red, white and blue attack dog can save you!
回头见
I'll see you soon.
叫罗德立刻找出这个疯子
Tell Rhodes, find this lunatic right now.
总统先生  我们追踪了广播的信号
Sir, we tracked the broadcast signal.
信号源可能位于巴基斯坦
We have a possible point of origin in Pakistan
爱国者已准备出击
and the Patriot is ready to strike.
马上出击
Right now!
明白
Yes, sir.
行动中失踪
不许动
Don't move!
请稍等
Hang on a second.
喂
Hello.
你试过被妹子骑在身上的时候抬头一看
Did you ever have a chick straddling you and you look up
她突然从内向外地发光
and suddenly she's glowing from the inside out,
变成亮橙色吗
kind of a bright orange?
试过  你是谁
Yeah, I've had that. Who is this?
是我  兄弟  上次我失踪的时候
It's me, pal. Now last time I went missing,
如果我没记错的话
if I remember correctly,
你来找我了  你在干什么呢
you came looking for me. What are you doing?
在巴基斯坦敲门谈话交朋友
A little knockin' talking, making friends in Pakistan.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
是AIM重新设计了你的战衣吗
Your re-design, your big re-brand, that was AIM, right?
没错
Yeah.
我得找个大通讯卫星  需要你的账号
I'm gonna find a heavy-duty comsat right now, I need your login.
一直都是那个账号  战争机器68
It's the same as it's always been, War Machine 68.
密码呢
And password please?
每次被你黑了我都得改密码  托尼
Well, look, I gotta change it every time you hack in, Tony.
现在不是80年代
It's not the eighties,
"被黑"这词已经过时了  告诉我密码
nobody says 'hack' anymore. Give me your login.
战争机器牛逼闪闪  全部大写
War Machine Rox with an X, all caps.
尽情地笑吧
Yeah, okay.
这比钢铁爱国者好多了
That is so much better than Iron Patriot.
哈密尔顿县纪念堂  查塔努加小姐圣诞选美大赛
很好  很好
Very nice, very nice.
请回答问题
One question for you.
你今年想要什么圣诞礼物
What would you like for Christmas this year?
大卫
Well, David...
我们正在现场直播
We're broadcasting live...
再来一次  这次面向所有人
One more time, this time is for everybody, all right.
网速慢
这可不行
That ain't gonna cut it.
对不起  先生  我不知道
Excuse me, sir. I don't know who...
妈  我等会儿再打给你  奇迹出现了
Mom, I need to call you back, something magical is happening.
托尼·斯塔克在我的车里
Tony Stark is in my van.
小点声
Keep it down.
托尼·斯塔克在我的车里
Tony Stark is in my van!
你认错人了
No, he's not.
我就知道你还活着
I knew you were still alive!
进来  关门
Come on in and close the door.
我能说句话吗  先生
Wow, can I just say, sir?
好的
Yeah.
我是你的超级脑残粉
I am your biggest fan.
我先问个问题  这是你的车吗
Okay. First, is this your van,
会不会有其他人进来
is anyone else gonna come in?
不不不  没人会进来
No, no, no. It's just us.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
加里
Gary.
保持距离
Right there's fine.
好的
Okay.
我经常遇到激动的粉丝  放松点
I get a lot of this, it's okay.
好  我能说句话吗
Oh, good. Can I just say?
你想说  说吧
What do you... yeah.
不知道你能不能看出来
I don't know if you can tell, but I have like,
但我在模仿你的造型
patterned my whole look after you.
-我的头发有点  不太对  -没事
- My hair's a little... it's not right. - It's fine.
-因为没喷发胶  -嗯
- Because there's no product in it. - Right.
-我不想让你尴尬  -没有
- I don't wanna make things awkward for you, - You're not.
但我得给你看这个
but I do have to show you... boom!
西班牙版的斯科特·拜奥
A Hispanic Scott Baio?
美国著名演员
对不起  这是我吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Is that me?
没错  这是照着我做的娃娃文上去的
Yeah. It's uh... I mean, I had them do it off a doll that I made,
所以跟照片不太像  有点
so it's not like it's off a picture. So it's a little bit...
加里  听我说
Gary, listen to me, okay?
我不想泼你冷水
I don't wanna clip your wings here,
我们都有点兴奋过头
we're both a little over-excited.
我有事  我在追查坏人
I got an issue. I'm chasing bad guys,
想从加密数据文件里找到线索
trying to grapple with something from some hard-crypt data files.
但这里网速不够
I don't have enough juice.
你得到车顶上去
I need you to jump on the roof, all right?
重新校准综合业务数字网
Recalibrate the ISDNs,
将功率提高40%
pump it up by about forty percent.
-懂了  -这是一项任务
- Got it. - Right, it's a mission.
好
Yeah.
托尼需要加里
Tony needs Gary.
-加里也需要托尼  -低调点
- And Gary needs Tony. - Be quiet about it.
-好  -去吧
- Yeah. - Go.
国家安全承包商  账号  战争机器68
拒绝访问
允许访问AIM系统
完全访问权限
查德·戴维斯中士
你觉得你这辈子的决定性时刻是什么时候
What would you regard as the defining moment of your life?
是我下定决心要战胜伤痛的那天
I think that'd be the day I decided not to let my injury beat me.
请对着摄像机说出你的名字
Will you please state your name for the camera?
艾伦·布兰特
Ellen Brandt.
好的  注射将定期进行
Okay. So, the injections are administered periodically.
不许喝酒或吸毒
Addiction will not be tolerated
不能自律的人将被赶出项目
and those who cannot regulate will be cut from the program.
你们曾经是局外人  残疾人
Once misfits, cripples...
但现在将成为人类进化的下一阶
you are the next iteration of human evolution.
绝境病毒项目  注射测试  第一阶段
大家好  开始之前  我向大家保证
Hi, everybody. Before we start, I promise you,
当你们回首往事
looking back at your life
最追悔莫及的将莫过于出于慎重
there will be nothing as bitter as the memory of that glorious risk
而决定放弃的美妙冒险
that you prudently elected to forego.
今天就是你们的荣耀之日  开始
Today is your glory. Let's begin!
我们得离开这里  快离开这里
We gotta get out of here! Gotta get out of here!
带他们走  带他们出去
Get 'em out! Get 'em out of here!
如果只是走火  就不算是炸弹了
A bomb is not a bomb when it's a misfire.
这东西并不总是好用  是吧  老兄
This stuff doesn't always work, right, pal?
它有缺陷  但你找到了买家  是吧
It's faulty, but you found a buyer, didn't you?
卖给了满大人  抓到你了
Sold it to the Mandarin. Got you.
到底怎么回事
What happened?
很有趣的事情
Fun fact:
在为纳粹制造火箭以前
before he built rockets for the Nazis,
理想主义的维尔纳·冯·布劳恩
the idealistic Werner von Braun
德国核物理学家和火箭专家  纳粹乙级战犯
幻想着航天旅行
dreamed of space travel,
他喜欢仰望星空
he stargazed.
第一枚V2火箭击中伦敦后
Do you know what he said
你知道他说了什么吗
when the first V2 hit London?
火箭运行得很完美
The rocket performed perfectly,
它只是落在了错误的星球上
it just landed on the wrong planet.
我们开始时都很天真
See we all begin wide-eyed,
纯粹的科学
pure science.
然后自大心开始作祟  变得痴迷
And then the ego steps in, the obsession. And...
抬头看时
you look up,
已经偏离了很远
you're a long way from shore.
你不要对自己太苛刻了  玛雅
You can't be too hard on yourself, Maya.
你把自己的研究交给了一个智囊团
I mean you gave your research to a think tank.
对  但基里安是靠军事合同建了那个智囊团
Yeah, but Killian built that think tank on military contracts.
我们以前也这么做  别自责了
That's exactly what we used to do, so don't judge yourself.
谢谢你  派珀
Thank you, Pepper.
我真的很感激
I really appreciate that.
晚上好
Hi, good evening.
-晚上好  -请进吧
- Good evening. - Come on in.
玛雅  快跑
Maya, run!
你好  派珀
Hi, Pepper.
你打算告诉我
So you want to tell me
你昨晚为什么会去斯塔克大宅吗
why you were at Stark's mansion last night?
我是想解决问题
I'm trying to fix this thing.
我又不知道你和大师打算把那里炸掉
I didn't know you and the Master were gonna blow the place up.
我明白了  所以你是想去救斯塔克
Oh, I see. So you were trying to save Stark,
尽管他威胁了我们
when he threatened us.
我说了  基里安  我们可以利用他
I told you, Killian, we can use him.
派珀  派珀  派珀
Pepper, Pepper, Pepper.
如果我们想在明年推出产品的话
Look if we wanna launch product next year,
我需要斯塔克
I need Stark.
他只是缺一个合适的动机  现在他有了
He just lacked a decent incentive. Now he has one.
我是支援队B0
This is Support Team Blue Zero,
向您发送疑似满大人信号发出点坐标
sending coordinates for suspected Mandarin broadcast point of origin.
收到
Copy.
不许动
Nobody move!
目标没有武器
支援队B0
Support Blue Zero,
除非满大人对美国的下场攻击
unless the Mandarin's next attack on the U.S.
与廉价运动装有关
involves cheaply-made sportswear,
否则我认为你们又搞错了
I think you messed up again.
没错  你们自由了
Yes, you're free, uh...
如果之前不自由的话
if you weren't before.
当然  是  女士
It's...of course. Yes ma'am.
钢铁爱国者执行任务  很乐意帮助您
Iron Patriot on the job. Happy to help,
不用谢我  我很荣幸
no need to thank me, it's my pleasure.
萨文  我拿到了爱国者战衣
Savin, I've acquired the Patriot armor.
你想要这套战衣
You want this suit?
你得先杀死我  把我从里面撬出来
You're gonna have to pry my cold, dead body out of it.
计划就是这样的  上校
That's the plan, Colonel.
哈里  告诉我进行的怎么样了
Harley, tell me what's happening,
我要听详细报告
give me a full report.
好的  我还在吃糖  你...
Yeah, I'm still eating that candy, do you want...
你要我继续吃吗
do you want me to keep eating it?
你吃了多少
How much did you have?
两三盆吧
Two or three bowls.
你还能看清吗
Can you still see straight?
差不多
Sort of.
说明你没事  电话给贾维斯
That means you're fine. Give me Jarvis.
贾维斯  情况怎么样
Jarvis, how are we?
完全没问题  先生
It's totally fine, sir.
有一段还不错
I seem to do quite well for a stretch
但在句子结尾的时候
and then at the end of the sentence
我说错了蔓越莓
I say the wrong cranberry.
还有  先生  你是对的
And, sir, you were right.
我把AIM下行设施考虑进去后
Once I factored in available AIM downlink facilities,
就定位到了满大人的广播信号
I was able to pinpoint the Mandarin's broadcast signal.
大概在哪里  远东  欧洲
What're we talkin'? Far East, Europe,
北非  伊朗  巴基斯坦  叙利亚  在哪
North Africa, Iran, Pakistan, Syria, where is it?
实际上  先生  在迈阿密
Actually, sir, it's in Miami.
好的
Okay.
孩子  我得一步步教你
Kid, I'm gonna have to walk you through
重启贾维斯的语音驱动
rebooting Jarvis' speech drive,
不过现在不行
but not right now.
哈里  他到底在哪
Harley, where is he really?
看一下屏幕  告诉我位置
Just look on the screen and tell me where it is.
显示的就是佛罗里达迈阿密
It does say Miami, Florida
好  先说重要的  我需要战衣
Okay, first things first, i need the armor.
它现在怎么样了
Where are we at with it?
充不了电
It's not charging.
实际上  先生  是在充电
Actually, sir, it's charging,
不过电源有问题
but the power source is questionable.
可能无法使马克42型恢复动力
It may not succeed in revitalizing the Mark 42.
电源有什么问题
What's questionable about electricity?
好吧  这是我的战衣
Alright, it's my suit
我不能...我不要...
and I can't... I'm not gonna...
我不想
I don't wanna...
-老天  又来了  -托尼
- Oh God, not again. - Tony?
你又发作了吗
Are you having another attack?
我都没提到纽约呢
I didn't even mention New York.
好吧  你刚刚说出来了
Right, and then you just said it, by name,
你还说你没说
while denying having said it!
好吧
Okay...
天啊  我怎么办
Oh, God. What am I gonna do?
深呼吸  真的  深呼吸
Just breathe. Really, just breathe.
你是机械师  对吧
You're a mechanic, right?
对
Right.
你是这么说的
You said so.
对  没错
Yes, I did.
那你为什么不造点东西呢
Why don't you just build something?
好
Okay,
多谢  孩子
thanks kid.
花盛牌化肥
火蚁控制
佛罗里达州  迈阿密
这里怎么这么热
Why is it so hot in here?
我说了要调到20度
I told you to put it at sixty-eight.
又是我的错  告诉你  亲爱的
My fault again. Let me tell you something sweetheart,
我不是你的个人
I am not your personal...
好吧
Well,
20分钟内最好别进去
I wouldn't go in there for twenty minutes!
好了  你们俩谁是凡妮莎
Now, which one of you is Vanessa?
是我
That's me.
妮茜  你知不知道
Ah, Nessie! Did you know
福饼不是中国发明的
that fortune cookies aren't even Chinese?
那边有个男人
There's some guy over here...
它们是美国人做的
They're made by Americans,
根据日本食谱做的
based on...based on the Japanese recipes.
完蛋了  完蛋了
Bloody hell. Bloody hell.
不许动
Don't move.
我没动  你想要什么就拿走吧
I'm not moving. If you want something, take it,
不过这些枪都是假的
although the guns are all fake
因为那些贱人不相信我  不肯给真的
because those wankers wouldn't trust me with the real ones.
什么
What?
这两个小妞你喜欢哪个吗
Hey, do you fancy either of the birds?
够了  你不是他
Heard enough. You're not him.
真的满大人  他在哪
The Mandarin, the real guy, where?!
满大人在哪  他在哪
Where's the Mandarin?! Where is he?!
他就在这  就在这
He's here. He's here.
但又不在这  他在这  又不在这
But he's not here. He's here, but he's not here.
-你什么意思  -情况很复杂
- What do you mean? - It's complicated.
-很复杂好吗  -是吗
- Hey, it's complicated, alright? - It is?
很复杂
It's complicated.
那就说清楚  女士请出去
Uncomplicate it. Ladies out.
从床上下来  到洗手间去
Get out of the bed, get in the bathroom.
坐下
Sit.
我叫特雷夫  特雷夫·斯拉特里
My name is Trevor, Trevor Slattery.
你是什么人
What are you?
幌子吗  你是个替身吧
What're you a decoy? You're a double, right?
什么  就像替补演员吗  当然不是
What? Like an understudy? No, absolutely not.
别打脸  我是个演员
Don't hurt the face! I'm an actor.
你还剩一分钟的命  好好说
You got a minute to live, fill it with words.
只是个角色
Just a role.
满大人  是虚构出来的
'The Mandarin', see, it's not real.
那你是怎么到这的  特雷夫
Then how did you get here, Trevor?
我有点小毛病
I um... I have a little problem with,
滥用药物什么的  结果
substances, and I ended up,
我做了些没办法的事
doing things, no two ways about it.
街头交易  男人不该做的事
In the street that a man shouldn't do.
接着说
Next!
然后
And then,
他们找到了我来扮演这个角色
they approached me about the role
他们也知道毒品的事
and they knew about the drugs.
他们怎么说的  帮你戒掉吗
What did they say they'd get you off 'em?
他们说会给我更多
Said they'd give me more.
他们给了我很多东西  给了我这座宫殿
They gave me things,they gave me this palace.
给我整了容  给了我好多东西
They gave me plastic surgery. They gave me things.
你是睡着了吗
Did you just nod off?
没有  还有一艘不错的快艇
No! And a lovely speedboat!
条件就是
And the thing was,
他需要个人
he needed someone
为一些"意外爆炸"负责
to take credit for some 'accidental explosions'.
他
He?
-基里安吗  -基里安
- Killian? - Killian.
-他编造了你  -他编造了我
- He created you? - He created me.
量身定制的恐怖威胁
Custom-made terror threat.
没错  没错
Yes! Yes!
是他的智囊团想出来的
His think tank thinked it up,
连环杀手的病态心理
the pathology of the serial killer.
利用了西方肖象学
The manipulation of Western iconography.
准备好再上一课了吗  诸如此类的
Ready for another lesson? Blah blah blah.
当然了  我的表演让这满大人栩栩如生
Of course, it was my performance that brought the Mandarin to life.
你的表演
Your performance?
还杀人呢
Where people die?
他们没死
No, they didn't.
看看这一切啊
Look around you,
服装  绿幕
costumes, green screen.
说实话  片子里一半的戏我都没到场
Oh, honestly, I wasn't on location for half this stuff.
有我的时候  是电影特效嘛  亲爱的
When I was, it was movie magic, love.
抱歉  不过我有个铁哥们正在昏迷中
I'm sorry,  but I got a best friend who's in a coma
也许醒不过来了
and he might not wake up.
所以你得为此负责
So you're gonna have to answer for that.
你还是要付出代价  哥们  你明...
You're still going down, pal. You under...
好了  特雷夫  你跟他说什么了
Okay, Trevor, what'd you tell him?
我什么都没说
I didn't tell him anything.
什么都没说
Nothing?
没有
No.
你该按应急按钮的
You should've pressed the panic button.
我是急了会儿  但我应付下来了
Well I panicked, but then I handled it.
好吧
Okay.
就跟以前一样  对吧
Just like old times, huh?
对  束线带绑着  真好玩
Oh yeah, with zip-ties. It's a ball.
那不是我的主意
It wasn't my idea.
看来你真收下了基里安的名片
Okay, so you took Killian's card.
我拿了他的钱
I took his money.
然后13年后  你困在这个地牢里
And here you are, thirteen years later in a dungeon.
不是
No.
是的
Yeah.
不是  是你困在地牢里  我想走就能走
No, you're in a dungeon. I'm free to go.
好吧
Yeah.
发生了很多事  托尼  不过我快成功了
A lot's happened, Tony, but I'm close.
绝境病毒已经很稳定了
Extremis is practically stable.
相信我它并没有
I'm telling you it isn't!
我去街上看过  很多人都爆炸了
I'm on the street, people are going 'bang',
溅了一墙血  玛雅  你是在欺骗自己
they're painting the walls. Maya, you're kidding yourself.
那就帮我修好它
Then help me fix it.
你知道我是谁
这是我写的
Did I do that?
对
Yes.
我记得那天晚上  但不记得早上了
I remember the night, not the morning.
你就是为了这个吗
Is this what you've been chasing around?
你不记得了
You don't remember?
帮不了你
I can't help you.
你以前是有道德心
You used to have a moral psychology.
有理想
You used to have ideals.
你想帮助别人
You wanted to help people,
看看你现在
now look at you.
现在每天早上陪我醒来的人
I get to wake up every morning with someone who...
是有灵魂的
still has her soul.
帮我出去
Get me out of here.
拜托了
Come on.
你知道我老爸以前是怎么跟我说的吗
You know what my old man used to say to me?
他最喜欢说的一句话是
One of his favorite of many sayings,
早起的鸟儿有虫吃
'The early bird gets the worm,
但是第二只老鼠有奶酪吃
but the second mouse gets the cheese.'
你不是还在为瑞士的事生气吧
You're not still pissed about the Switzerland thing, are you?
我怎么能生你的气呢  托尼
How can I be pissed at you, Tony?
我是来感谢你的
I'm here to thank you.
你送了我一份这辈子最棒的礼物
You gave me the greatest gift that anybody's ever given me.
绝望
Desperation.
回想一下在瑞士的时候
If you think back to Switzerland,
你说会去楼顶找我  是吧
you said you'd meet me on the rooftop, right?
头二十分钟
Well for the first twenty minutes,
我真以为你会来
I actually thought you'd show up.
接下来的一小时里
And the next hour, I...
我考虑着
well I considered taking that
跨出一步  走近路去大堂
one step shortcut to the lobby,
你明白我的意思吗
if you know what I mean.
坦白说  我还在想
Honestly, I'm still trying to
第一只老鼠发生了什么事
figure out what happened to the first mouse.
不过当我俯瞰那座城市时
But as I looked out over that city,
没人知道我在那里
nobody knew I was there,
没人看得见我  甚至没人在看
nobody could see me, no one was even looking.
我冒出了一个今后引导了我多年的想法
I had a thought that would guide me for years to come.
就是隐姓埋名  托尼
Anonymity, Tony.
多亏了你  这从此成了我的准则  对吧
Thanks to you, it's been my mantra ever since, right?
你只需要在幕后运筹帷幄
You simply rule from behind the scenes.
因为一旦你赋予了邪恶一副面孔
Because the second you give evil a face,
本·拉登  卡扎菲  或是满大人
a Bin Laden, a Gaddafi, The Mandarin,
你就给了人们一个靶子
you hand the people a target.
你真不是一般人
You're something else.
你已经见过他了吧
You have met him, I assume?
是啊  影帝先生
Yeah, Sir Lawrence Olivier.
我知道他有时候有点夸张
I know he's a little over the top sometimes.
这不能怪我
It's not entirely my fault,
他比较...他是个舞台剧演员
he has a tend...he's a stage actor.
据说他演的李尔王在克罗伊登很受欢迎  管他呢
They say his Lear was the toast of Croydon, wherever that is.
总之  重点是
Anyway, the point is,
自从那个拿锤子的大块头从天而降之后
ever since that big dude with the hammer fell out of the sky,
低调就不流行了
subtlety's kinda had its day.
你接下来打算做什么
What's next for you in your world?
我想回馈给你
Well, I wanted to repay you
你曾慷慨给予我的东西
with the same gift that you so graciously imparted to me.
绝望
Desperation.
这是直播
Now, this is live.
我不确定你是否了解状况
I'm not sure if you can tell,
此刻她的身体正在试图决定
but at this moment the body is trying to decide
是接受绝境病毒还是直接放弃
whether to accept Extremis or just give up.
如果她放弃了  我只能说那场面
And if it gives up, I have to say the denotation is...
是相当震撼的
it's quite spectacular.
不过在做出决定之前  只有巨大的痛苦
But until that point, it's really just a lot of pain.
我们还没讨论过薪酬呢
We haven't even talked salary yet.
你还想要什么福利
What kind of perk package are you thinking of? Hm?
放开他
Let him go.
稍等  稍等
Hold on, hold on.
玛雅
Maya...
我说了放了他
I said let him go!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
1200毫升  只要一半剂量就够致死了
1200cc's, a dose half of this size, I'm dead.
总有人考验我的耐心
It's times like these my temper is tested somewhat.
玛雅  把注射器给我
Maya, give me the injector.
基里安  我要是死了你的士兵们会怎样
If I die, Killian, what happens to your soldiers?
你的产品又会怎样
What happens to your product?
我们用不着这样  好吗
We're not doing this, okay?
你自己会怎样  要是你过热了怎么办
What happens to you? What happens if you go too hot?
好消息是  高层现在有一个空职了
The good news is, a high level position has just been vacated.
你就是个疯子
You're a maniac.
错  我是个远见家
No, I'm a visionary.
但我手下的确有个疯子
But I do own a maniac,
今晚就看他的表演了
and he takes the stage tonight.
一旦钢铁爱国者成功登机
Once we get the Patriot installed,
我只要九到十分钟就能搞定
it'll take me nine...ten minutes for a take down.
那太好了
Well, that's great.
但是上一次看到它里面还有人呢
But the last time I looked there was somebody inside of it.
下午好  先生们
Afternoon, gentlemen.
你好  上校
Hello, Colonel.
都让开
Step aside.
我们会让你出来的  别担心
We'll get you out of there, don't worry.
这样会破坏战甲的
You'll damage the armor.
是啊
Yes, I will.
但你会修好的  对吗
But you can fix it, right?
我要带战衣去基地
I'm gonna take the suit up to base camp,
波茨也跟我一起去
and I want Potts with me.
她还在第二阶段
She's still in Phase 2.
你听不懂我说的话吗
You're not going deaf, are you?
小心点  那可是限量版
Careful there, it's a limited edition.
恶搞小马快递  一种桌游
小马尾快递
Ponytail Express.
田纳西离迈阿密有多远
What's the mileage count between Tennessee and Miami?
832英里
Eight hundred and thirty-two miles.
非常好
Very nice.
我比较擅长这个
I'm good like that.
你能  把那玩意儿停掉吗
Can you, uh...stop that?
弄坏了你就赔
Break it, you bought it!
我赔就是了
I think I bought it.
那可不是我的
Okay, that wasn't mine to give away.
是我朋友的妹妹的
That belongs to my friend's sister,
所以我等会要先杀你
and that's why I'm gonna kill you first.
-你要怎么杀我  -等着瞧吧
- What're you gonna do to me? - You'll see.
你现在被绑在一张床上
You're zip-tied to a bed.
像这样
This.
像那样
That.
你打算出来了吗
Are you comin' out?
不要打开  不要打开
Do not open, do not open!
别打开  别打开  别
Don't open, don't open, don't...!
那还是出去吧
Alright, let's go.
你还能喷火
You...you breathe fire?
好吧
Okay.
真是美妙的一天  萨文
It's a glorious day, Savin.
明天这个时候
This time tomorrow,
整个西方最有权力的领导人
I'll have the West's most powerful leader in one hand,
以及最可怕的恐怖分子都会在我手里
and the world's most feared terrorist in the other.
我会控制整个反恐战争
I'll own the War on Terror.
为这个世界创造供需
Creates supply and demand
为了你和你的兄弟姐妹们
for you and your brothers and sisters.
相信我
Trust me,
你们距离倒在血泊中还剩
you're gonna be in a puddle of blood on the ground
五  四  三  拜托  二
in five, four, three...come on! Two...
我们怎么会摊上这个傻逼
How did we get this shit?
我给你们个机会现在就逃
Alright, I'm gonna give you a chance to escape.
放下武器
Put down your weapons,
把自己绑在椅子上
tie yourselves to those chairs,
我就不杀你们  还有五  四
I'll let you live. In five, four...bang!
那还真是
That was...
你们应该死了
You should be gone by now,
这会就该上西天了才对
you should have already been gone.
我真是要吓尿了
I am just beyond terrified.
来了  三  四
Here it comes. Three, four...
闭嘴
Shut up.
五  四  三  二  一
Five, four, three, two, one!
早跟你说了
Told ya.
剩下的部分呢
Where's the rest?
说实话  我讨厌在这工作
Honestly, I hate working here.
他们是群怪胎
They are so weird.
晚了总比不来好
Ah, better late than never.
这次不要  别撞脸
Not this time. Not the face.
回来真好  对了  你好
Phew, it's good to be back. Hello, by the way.
你好  先生
Oh, hello sir.
钢铁爱国者
全体注意  斯塔克已逃脱
All personnel, Stark is loose
正在院子里某处
and somewhere in the compound.
重复  斯塔克已逃脱
Repeat, Stark is loose
正在院子里某处
and somewhere in the compound.
我们走吧
Let's go.
该死
Ah, crap.
托尼
Tony...
罗德  那是你穿着战衣吧
Rudy, tell me that was you in the suit.
不是  你拿到你的了吗
No. You got yours?
算是吧  尽快赶到主屋去
Kind of. Main house as fast as you can.
我要介绍个人给你认识
Somebody I'd like you to meet.
你  你  还有你  出去  快滚
You, you, move! Get out!
房间安全  已看到满大人
The room is secure. I have eyes on the Mandarin.
这是什么  我赢了
What's this? I had winner's.
你扮成了什么
What've you come as?
你敢动一下我就打爆你的脸
You make a move and I'll break your face.
我从来不知道有人受了伤  他们骗了我
I never thought people had been hurt. They lied to me.
这就是满大人
This is the Mandarin?
我知道  这...太丢人了
I know, it's...it's...it's embarrassing.
我是特雷夫  特雷夫·斯拉特里
Hi, Trevor. Trevor...Slattery.
我知道  我本人有点矮  有点瘦
I know, I'm shorter in person, bit small,
每个人都这么说  但是
everyone says that. But...
如果你们是来抓我的
if you're here to arrest me,
我乐意马上供出一些人来
there are some people who I'd like to roll on. Immediately.
我来跟你说明下状况  梅姨
Here's how it works, Meryl Streep.
你告诉他派珀在哪  我才会停下
You tell him where Pepper is and I'll stop doin' it.
停下什么
Doing what?
我懂了  好疼  我懂了  我懂了
Oh, I get it! Ow! That hurt! I get it! I get it!
我不知道派珀是谁
I don't know about any Pepper,
-但我知道他们的计划  -快说
- but I know about the plan. - Spill.
你知道他们把我的战衣怎么了吗
Do you know what they did to my suit?
什么  不  但我知道地点是在海岸
What? No. But I do know what's happening off the coast.
跟一艘大船有关
Something to do with uh...A big boat.
我可以带你们过去
I can take you there.
托尼  我发誓  我一定要打烂他的脸
Tony, I swear to God. I'm gonna blow his face off.
而且这事还跟副总统有关系
Oh, this next bit may include the Vice President as well.
这个重要吗
Is that...is that important?
算是吧
Somewhat.
挺重要的
Yeah, a little bit.
怎么样
So?
我们怎么办  没有交通工具
What are we gonna do? I mean, we don't have any transport.
披头士成员之一
林戈  你是不是提过有一艘不错的快艇
Ringo. Didn't you say something about a 'lovely speedboat'?
如果他说的地点没错
If he's right about the location,
我们离派珀还有20分钟的路程
we're twenty minutes from where Pepper is.
但我们还得搞清楚副总统的事  对吧
But we also have to figure out this Vice President thing, right?
没错  猜我正在打给谁
Right. I wonder who I'm calling right now?
是副总统
Oh, that's the Vice President.
谢谢
Thanks.
你好
Hello.
我是托尼·斯塔克
Sir, this is Tony Stark.
欢迎回到人间
Welcome back to the land of the living.
我们有理由相信
We believe you're about to be
您可能会被卷入满大人的袭击事件
drawn into the Mandarin campaign,
我们得尽快将您转移到安全地点
and we gotta get you somewhere safe as soon as possible.
斯塔克先生  我正准备在精英特工的保护下
Mr. Stark, I'm about to eat honey roast ham
享用蜜汁火腿
surrounded by the agency's finest.
而总统和罗德上校在空军一号上
The President's safe on Air Force One with Colonel Rhodes,
我认为我们都很安全
I think we're good here.
先生  我是罗德上校
Sir, this is Colonel Rhodes!
他们打算用钢铁爱国者做木马
They're using the Iron Patriot as a Trojan Horse,
想办法干掉总统
they're gonna take out the President somehow.
我们得立刻警告机组
We have to immediately alert that plane.
好的  我会让安保人员马上行动
Okay, I'm on it. I'll have security lock it down.
如果情况需要  F22战机30秒内就能就位
If need be, they can have F22s in the air in thirty seconds.
谢谢你  上校
Thank you, Colonel.
罗德和斯塔克结束通话
Rhodes and Stark out.
没什么问题吧  先生
Everything okay, sir?
完全没有
Couldn't be better.
我爱你  宝贝
I love you, baby.
罗德上校  你能过来真是太好了
Colonel Rhodes. Glad to see you could make it, son.
我这就感觉安全多了
I feel safer already.
我们得做个决定
We gotta make a decision.
总统和派珀只能救其一
We can either save the President or Pepper.
没法同时救两边
We can't do both.
先生  马里布那边有新情况
Sir, I have an update from Malibu.
起重机总算到达了现场
The cranes have finally arrived
正在清理地下室入口
and the cellar doors are being cleared as we speak.
我身上的战衣现在什么状态
And what about the suit I'm wearing?
能量已经充到92%了
The armor is now at ninety-two percent.
也只能凑合用了
That's gonna have to do.
他过来了  他过来了  给我来张合照
Oh, here he comes, here he comes, get a quick picture.
没问题
Sure.
一切正常吧  上校
Everything all right, Colonel?
真是荣幸啊  总统先生
It is an honor, Mr. President.
你要动手  就动手吧
If you're gonna do it, do it.
别着急啊  先生
Cool your boots, sir.
这可不是满大人的作风
That's not how the Mandarin works.
长官  空军一号陷入危急状态
Sir, Air Force One's been compromised.
内部发生射击  温度骤升
Internal shots, temperature spikes.
快把画面调出来
Get me eyes on it now.
画面出来了  长官
Image coming through now, sir.
那是罗德吗
Was that Rhodes?
总统呢
The President.
快说
Now.
他不在这里
He's not here.
去享受喷流吧
Try the jet stream.
说到气流  去捞鱼吧
Speaking of which, go fish!
看这个伤口还愈合得了吗  狗娘养的
Walk away from that, you son of a bitch.
下面有多少人
How many in the air?
13个  先生
Thirteen, sir.
我一次能带几个
How many can I carry?
四个  先生
Four, sir.
慢点  慢点  放松  你叫什么
Slow down, slow down. Relax, what's your name?
希瑟
Heather...
听我说  看到那个人了吗
Listen to me. See that guy?
我会飞过去  然后你抓住他
I'm gonna swing by and you're just gonna grab him.
-明白了吗  -什么
- You got it?  - What?
我会让你的手臂通上电
I will electrify your arm,
这样你就松不开手了
you won't be able to open your hand.
你能做到的  希瑟
You can do this, Heather.
简单吧  还有11个
Easy, see? Eleven more to go.
记不记得有个叫猴子冒险的游戏
Remember that game called Barrel of Monkeys?
我们就那么玩
That's what we're gonna do.
高度一万八千英尺
Eighteen thousand feet.
大家加油  每个人都抓好自己的猴子
Come on, people! Everybody, grab your monkey!
漂亮
Nice!
一万英尺
Ten thousdand feet.
六千英尺
Six thousand feet.
大家加油
Come on, people.
加油  加油  加油
Come on, come on, come on!
一千英尺
One thousand feet.
四百英尺
Four hundred feet.
两百英尺
Two hundred feet, sir.
是只胖猴子  抓住他
It's a chunky monkey, let's get him.
你好
Hello.
干得漂亮
Nice work, guys.
太棒了  大家配合得很好
Excellent. Good team effort all around. Go us.
贾维斯  这才算完成一半
Alright, Jarvis, but it's only half done,
我们还得去找派珀
we still gotta get Pepp...
从哪冒出来的
That came out of nowhere.
跟我说点好消息
Give me some good news, man.
全部获救了
I think they all made it.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
但是总统被抓走了
Yeah, but I missed the President.
你有战衣都救不了总统
You couldn't save the President with the suit,
我们什么都没有怎么救派珀
how are we gonna save Pepper with nothing?
贾维斯  时间到了吗
Say, Jarvis, is it that time?
是家庭聚会规程吗  先生
The 'house party' protocol, sir?
没错
Correct.
你以为他会帮你吗
You think he's gonna help you...
不可能
He won't.
把你抓来不单是刺激托尼·斯塔克
Having you here is not just to motivate Tony Stark,
其实还有更尴尬的目的
it's um...it's actually more embarrassing than that.
你在这里是我的
You're here as my, um...
战利品
Trophy.
晚上好  先生
Good evening, sir.
欢迎上船  总统先生
Welcome aboard, Mr. President.
罗克森公司诺克号
听说过大象墓地吗
Ever hear of an elephant graveyard?
两年前
Well, two years ago,
这艘驳船就是大象
the elephant in the room was this scow.
这是罗克森诺克号
This is the Roxxon Norco.
你当然记得了
And of course you'll remember
它在彭萨科拉附近泄露了一百万加仑原油
that when she spilled a million gallons of crude off Pensacola,
拜您所赐  没有一个富人受到法庭审判
thanks to you, not one fat cat saw a day in court.
你要我怎么样
What do you want from me?
不怎么样  先生
Nothing, sir.
我只是需要个在电视上处决你的好借口
I just needed a reason to kill you that would play well on TV.
我已经向前看了
You see, I've moved on.
我找到了新政治靠山
I've found myself a new political patron,
明天这个时候  他将接替你的职位
and at this time tomorrow, he'll have your job.
绑起来
String him up.
这边
Come on.
你不会突然抓狂吧
You're not gonna freak out on me, right?
希望不会
I hope not.
天啊
Oh, my God.
他被吊在油罐上面
He's strung up over the oil tank,
他们要点火烧死他  老兄
they're gonna light him up, man.
维京葬礼  公开处决
Viking funeral. Public execution.
对  用油烧死
Yeah, death by oil.
直播即将开始  各就各位
Broadcast will commence shortly. Take final positions.
很好  镜头从A切换到E
Okay, that's good. Now give me cameras A through E
先预演下
and we'll do a full tech rehearsal.
枪举好了吗
Is your gun up?
好了  我要干嘛
Yep. What do I do?
6点钟方向  注意高处  别走火打我后背
Stay on my six, cover high, and don't shoot me in the back.
6点  高处  后背  好了
Six, high, back. Alright.
看到了吗  搞定
You see that? Nailed it.
没错  你把灯泡打爆了
Yeah, you really killed the glass.
我瞄的就是灯泡  这么远你肯定打不准
I was aiming for the bulb! You can't hit a bulb at this distance.
我没弹药了
I'm out.
有多余弹匣吗
Give me...give me...you got an extra magazine?
不通用的  托尼
They're not universal, Tony.
我知道我在干嘛  我造这玩意的
I know what I'm doing, I make this stuff.
-好吧  -再给我一个
- Okay.  - Give me another one.
我没有适合那把枪的
I don't have one that fits that gun.
你有五个呢  好吧
You've got like five of 'em.
这样吧  我来侦查  准备好了吗
Alright, here's what I'm gonna do. I'm gonna spot. Ready?
你看到什么了
What'd you see?
太快了  什么都没看到
Too fast, nothing.
再来一次
Here we go.
三男一女  有武器
Three guys, one girl, all armed.
上帝  我现在想死战衣了
God, I'd kill for some armor right now.
说得没错  我们需要支援
You're right, we need backup.
大批支援
Yeah, a bunch.
话说...
You know what?
-那是  -对
- Is...is that?  -Yep.
-那全是  -对
- Are those? - Yeah.
双子星
马克39型
碎心者
马克17型
猎枪
马克40型
红鲷鱼
马克35型
银色百夫长
马克33型
圣诞快乐  老兄
Merry Christmas, buddy.
贾维斯  定位绝境病毒热信号
Jarvis, target Extremis heat signatures.
废了他们
Disable with extreme prejudice.
收到
Yes, sir.
锤头鲨
马克37型
还等什么  圣诞节到了
What are you waiting for? It's Christmas.
送他们上天堂
Take 'em to church.
活塞
马克31型
骨骼
马克41型
先生们
Gentlemen.
来了
Incoming.
贾维斯  让伊戈尔去撑住
Jarvis, get Igor to steady this thing.
伊戈尔
马克38型
你休息的时候就在干这个
This is how you've been managing your downtime, huh?
人总得有点爱好
Everybody needs a hobby.
碎心者  去帮帮红鲷鱼
Heartbreaker? Help Red Snapper out, will ya?
时间刚刚好
Nice timing.
真棒  给我也来一套
Oh yeah, that's awesome. Give me a suit, okay?
银色百夫长
马克33型
抱歉  它们只能由我操控
Oh, I'm sorry. They're...they're only coded to me.
什么意思
What's that mean?
我让人掩护你
I got you covered.
碎心者
马克17型
晚上好  上校  要我载你一程吗
Good evening, Colonel. Can I give you a lift?
真好笑
Very funny.
突袭者
马克25型
先生  我已找到波茨小姐
Sir, I've located Miss Potts.
可算啊
About time.
停  放下  放下
Stop! Put it down, put it down, put it down.
看看你和我前女友出去的后果
See what happens when you hang out with my ex-girlfriends?
你就是个混蛋
You're such a jerk.
好啦  晚餐时再聊这个
Yep. We'll talk about it over dinner.
手伸过来  过来点  宝贝
Come on. A little more, baby.
这家伙在骚扰你吗
Is this guy bothering you?
别起来
Don't get up!
这样热吗
Is that hot in there?
不能动了  是不是
Stuck? Feel a little stuck?
像只小海龟  要在龟壳里烤熟了
Like a little turtle, cooking in his little turtle suit?
托尼
Oh, Tony.
她看着呢
She's watching.
我觉得你应该闭上眼睛  闭上眼睛
I think you should close your eyes. Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛  你不想看到的
Close your eyes, you don't wanna see this.
不着急  慢慢来
Yeah, you take a minute.
双子星
马克39型
贾维斯  给我一套战衣
Jarvis, give me a suit right now!
热棒
马克22型
拜托
Come on!
总统先生  坚持住  我来了
Mr. President! Just hold on,alright? I'm coming.
坚持住  坚持住
Just hold on. Hold on.
好吧
OK.
再见了
Bye-bye.
做好准备
Brace yourself!
你帅爆了  总统先生
You look damn good, Mr. President,
不过我得要回我的战衣
but I'm gonna need that suit back.
总统安全了  托尼  我得带他离开
The President is secure, Tony. I'm clearing the area.
做得好
Nice work.
准备好了吗  先生
Ready sir?
准备什么
What do you mean 'ready'?
小派  我来了  放松  我接着你
Pep, I got you. Relax, I got you.
看着我
Just look at me.
宝贝  我伸不了更远
Honey, I can't reach any further,
你不能待在那儿  好吗
and you can't stay there, alright?
你得放手
You gotta let go.
放手  我保证能接住你
You gotta let go! I'll catch you, I promise!
真可惜
What a shame,
要是我就能接住她
I would have caught her.
夜店
马克16型
弹出
Eject.
猎枪
马克40型
我们终于在屋顶碰面了
Well here we are, on the roof.
马克42型到达
Mark 42 inbound.
哎呦喂
Well I'll be damned.
浪子归来了
The prodigal son returns.
算了
Whatever.
你真的配不上她  托尼
You really didn't deserve her, Tony.
真遗憾  我就要把她改造得  完美了
It's a pity, I was so close to having her... perfect.
好吧  等等  等等
Okay, okay! Wait, wait! Slow down, slow down!
你说得对
You're right,
我配不上她
I don't deserve her!
但是你错了  她本就很完美了
Here's where you're wrong, she was already perfect.
贾维斯  帮我炸掉马克42型
Jarvis, do me a favor and blow Mark 42.
不
Noooo!
鬼祟
马克15型
别再戴面具了
No more false faces.
你说你想找满大人
You said you wanted the Mandarin,
我就是
you're looking right at him.
一直都是我  托尼  从一开始就是
It was always me, Tony, right from the start.
我就是满大人
I am the Mandarin!
我说不出话
I got nothin'.
马克9型
贾维斯  我12点钟方向的不是目标
Jarvis, subject at my twelve o'clock is not a target,
解除武装
disengage!
怎么  生我气了吗
What? Oh, what, are you mad at me?
宝贝
Honey.
天哪
Oh, my God.
刚刚好暴力
That was really violent.
你吓死我了  我还以为你
You just scared the devil out of me. I thought you were...
死了吗  为什么
I was dead. Why?
因为我从200英尺处掉了下来
Because I fell two hundred feet?
现在是谁一团糟了
Who's the hot mess now?
有待讨论
It's still debatable.
可能还是你
Probably tipping your way a little bit.
你何不在家也这么穿
Why don't you dress like this at home?
运动文胸什么的
Sport bra, the whole deal.
我能理解
You know, I think I understand
你为什么不肯放弃这些战衣了
why you don't want to give up the suits.
我还能抱怨什么呢
What I am gonna complain about now?
对于我
Well, it's me.
你总能想到的
You'll think of somethin'.
-过来  宝贝  -别碰我
- Come here, babe. -  No, don't touch me!
-不  没事的  -我会烫伤你的
- No, don't worry about it.  - No, I'm gonna burn you!
不不  不会的
No, no, you're not.
你看  不烫
See. Not hot.
我会没事吗
Am I gonna be okay?
不  你在和我谈恋爱
No, you're in a relationship with me,
总是会有事的
everything will never be okay.
但是我觉得这我搞得定
But I think I can figure this out, yeah.
20年前我喝醉时  还差点琢磨出来了
I almost had this twenty years ago when I was drunk.
我觉得我能让你好起来
I think I can get you better.
我就擅长这个  修理东西
That's what I do, I fix stuff.
你的那些"消遣"呢
And all your distractions?
我会削减一下
I'm gonna shave them down a little bit.
贾维斯
Jarvis?
都结束了  先生  还有事吗
All wrapped up here, sir. Will there be anything else?
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
库存清理规程吗  先生
The 'clean slate' protocol, sir?
不管了  圣诞节嘛  是的
Screw it, it's Christmas. Yes, yes.
还行吧  你喜欢吗
Okay so far? You like it?
这就行了
It'll do.
随着圣诞节早晨的到来
And so, as Christmas morning began,
我的旅程也到达终点
my journey had reached its end.
你始于纯粹的初衷
You start with something pure,
令人兴奋的想法
something exciting.
随之而来的是犯错
Then come the mistakes.
妥协
The compromises.
我们为自己埋下祸根
We create our own demons.
幸会
It's great to see you.
我如约稳定了派珀体内的绝境病毒
As promised, I got Pepper sorted out.
花了些功夫
It took some tinkering.
然后我又想  何必止步于此
But then I thought to myself, "Why stop there?"
当然  有人会说  前进有风险
Of course, there are people who say progress is dangerous.
但是我敢打赌那些傻瓜
But I'll bet none of those idiots
不用带着一胸腔的弹片生活
never had to live with a chest full of shrapnel.
现在  我也不用了
And now...neither will I.
告诉你  这是我这些年睡得最好的一次
Let me tell you, that was the best sleep I'd had in years.
没事了  没事了
It's ok, it's ok, it's ok.
土豆枪2型
你的朋友 机械师
如果要我给这一切加个好结尾
So if I were to wrap this up tight with a bow or whatever,
我猜我会说我的战衣
I guess I'd say my armor,
从不是什么消遣或爱好
it was never a distraction or a hobby,
而是茧
it was a cocoon.
现在  我破茧成蝶了
And now, I'm a changed man.
你可以拿走我的房子  花招和玩具
You can take away my house, all my tricks and toys.
有一样东西你永远拿不走
One thing you can't take away...
我就是钢铁侠
I am Iron Man.
钢铁侠3
谢谢你  听我说了这么多
You know, and thank you, by the way, for listening.
这感觉真的很棒
There's just something about getting it off my chest
把这些话说出来
and putting it out there in the atmosphere
而不是憋在心里
instead of holding this in.
否则人会生病的  是吧
I mean, this is what gets people sick, you know?
我都不知道你是个这么好的倾听者
Wow, I had no idea you were such a good listener.
能把我内心的想法
To be able to share all of my intimate thoughts
和经历与人分享
and my experiences with someone,
心里轻松了一半
it just cuts the weight of it in half, you know.
就像蛇吞食自己的尾巴
It's like a snake swallowing its own tale.
一切都圆满了
Everything comes full circle.
而且你能帮我应对...
And...and the fact that you've been able to help me process...
-讲到哪了  -你在听吗
- So, uh...? - You with me?
当然  我们讲到...
I was, yeah. We were... uh, we were at, uh...
你在打盹
You actively napping?
我神游了
I... I was... I... I... I drifted.
你在哪睡过去的
Where did I lose you?
瑞士的电梯
Elevator in Switzerland.
也就是说你什么都没听到
So you heard none of it?
抱歉  我不是那种医生
I'm sorry, I'm not that kind of doctor.
我不是治疗师  这不是我的长项
I'm not a therapist, it's not my training.
-那又如何  -我没有...
- So? - I don't have the...
什么  时间吗
What? The time?
那个性子
Temperament.
其实  仔细想起来
You know what? Now that I think about it,
天呐  我的原始创伤是在1983年
oh, God, my original wound. 1983, alright?
-嗯  -我都14了  还有保姆
- Yes. - I'm 14 years old, I still have a nanny?
太奇怪了
That was weird.
托尼·斯塔克还将回归